<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>BBC China News-全文</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/</link><description>This is the full text parser for feed &lt;BBC News - China&gt;</description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 11:25:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.0.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Coronavirus: Global death toll exceeds 3,000</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-51701039</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner" property="articleBody"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="Fans wear 3M Aura Disposable Respirators as they await kickoff prior to the Liga match, 1 March in Madrid, Spain" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/2511/production/_111098490_gettyimages-1209725544.jpg" width="976"/&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    Fans at the Real Madrid match this weekend were not taking any chances against the deadly coronavirus
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  The number of people killed worldwide by the coronavirus has exceeded 3,000, as China reported 42 more deaths.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  More than 90% of the total deaths are in Hubei, the Chinese province where the virus emerged late last year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But there have also been deaths in 10 other countries, including more than 50 in Iran and more than 30 in Italy.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Worldwide, there have been almost 90,000 confirmed cases, with the numbers outside China now growing faster than inside China.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But most patients have only mild symptoms, the World Health Organization said on Sunday, and the death rate appears to be between 2% and 5%.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div aria-hidden="true" class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /**/
            (function() {
                if (window.bbcdotcom &amp;&amp; bbcdotcom.adverts &amp;&amp; bbcdotcom.adverts.slotAsync) {
                    bbcdotcom.adverts.slotAsync('mpu', [1,2,3]);
                }
            })();
            /**/
   &lt;/script&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  By comparison, the seasonal flu has an average mortality rate of about 0.1% but is highly infectious - with up to 400,000 people dying from it each year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Other strains of coronavirus, such as Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome (SARS) and Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS), have much higher death rates.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  What's the global situation?
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As the rate of growth in China has declined, the rest of the world has seen a sharp increase in infections.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In the European hotspot of Italy, the number of infections doubled in 48 hours, the head of the country's civil protection body said on Sunday.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  There have been at least 34 deaths and 1,694 confirmed cases. Amazon said two of its employees in Italy have the virus and are under quarantine.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In the UK,
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-51700604"&gt;
   where there are 36 confirmed cases
  &lt;/a&gt;
  , Prime Minister Boris Johnson has called an emergency Cobra committee for Monday.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  On Monday, South Korea - the biggest hotspot outside China - reported 476 new cases, bringing the total number of cases to 4,212.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Of these, 3,081 cases are from the South Korean city of Daegu - and 73% of these cases have been linked to the Shincheonji Church.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load" data-alt="Death rates for different groups" data-height="2916" data-src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/F197/production/_111074816_death_ratio-nc.png" data-width="2666"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load" data-alt="Presentational white space" data-height="1" data-src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/94C2/production/_109028083_1px_white_line-nc.png" data-width="624"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Members of the fringe Christian group are believed to have infected one another and then fanned out around the country, apparently undetected.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In the capital Seoul, the mayor urged the city's 10 million residents to work from home and to avoid crowded places.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-asia-51695649"&gt;
    S Korea religious leader faces coronavirus probe
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Iran, one of the worst affected countries, said on Sunday that it had 978 infections and 54 deaths.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Countries including Qatar, Ecuador, Luxembourg and Ireland all confirmed their first cases over the weekend.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The US state of New York also confirmed its first case. The patient is a woman in her 30s who contracted the virus during a recent trip to Iran.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  One person has died in the US so far -
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-51692577"&gt;
   a man in his 50s with underlying health problems
  &lt;/a&gt;
  in the state of Washington.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  What's the situation in China?
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  China on Monday reported 42 more deaths, all in Hubei. There were also 202 confirmed new cases - only six of which were outside Hubei.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A total of 2,912 people have died inside China, with more than 80,000 confirmed cases of the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-asia-china-51276656"&gt;
    Diary of a life in locked-down Wuhan
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-asia-51691967"&gt;
    China pollution clears amid coronavirus slowdown
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/health-51674743"&gt;
    How deadly is the coronavirus?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A spokesman from China's National Health Commission said the next stop would be to "focus on the risks brought by the resumption of work".
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  China's economy has taken a hit - with factory activity falling at a record rate.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  US space agency Nasa found a dramatic decline in pollution levels this year, which is "at least partly" due to the economic slowdown prompted by the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load" data-alt="Presentational grey line" data-height="2" data-src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/1226D/production/_105894347_grey_line-nc.png" data-width="640"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  What do I need to know about the coronavirus?
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   WHAT ARE THE SYMPTOMS?
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51048366"&gt;
    A simple guide
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   WAYS TO PREVENT CATCHING IT:
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/av/health-51637561/coronavirus-watch-how-germs-spread"&gt;
    How to wash your hands
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   WHERE ARE WE WITH A VACCINE?
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51665497"&gt;
    Progress so far
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   A VISUAL GUIDE TO THE OUTBREAK:
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-51235105"&gt;
    Virus maps and charts
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   WHAT DOES IT MEAN FOR MY HOLIDAY?
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51615412"&gt;
    Your rights as a traveller
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load" data-alt="Presentational grey line" data-height="2" data-src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/1226D/production/_105894347_grey_line-nc.png" data-width="640"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  What has the WHO said?
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  On Sunday, the World Health Organization said the virus appears to particularly affect those over 60, and people already ill.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It urged countries to stock up on ventilators, saying "oxygen therapy is a major treatment intervention for patients with severe Covid-19".
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In the first large analysis of more than 44,000 cases from China, the death rate was ten times higher in the very elderly compared to the middle-aged.
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 03:16:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>China Uighurs 'moved into factory forced labour' for foreign brands</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-51697800</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="The outside of the Qingdao Taekwang Shoes Co. factory, where Uighur workers make shoes" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/5B49/production/_111096332_gettyimages-1204096838-1.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    The Taekwang factory is among those employing Uighurs
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  Thousands of Muslims from China's Uighur minority group are working under coercive conditions at factories that supply some of the world's biggest brands, a new report says.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The Australian Strategic Policy Institute said this was the next phase in China's re-education of Uighurs.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  China has already detained about a million Uighurs at internment camps, punishing and indoctrinating them.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Officials say the camps are aimed at countering extremism.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The ASPI report comes after a senior Chinese official told reporters in December that
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-50712126"&gt;
   members of the minority group being held in the camps had now "graduated".
  &lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  What does the report say?
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Between 2017 and 2019, the ASPI think tank estimates that more than 80,000 Uighurs were transferred out of the far western Xinjiang autonomous region to work in factories across China. It said some were sent directly from detention camps.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  ASPI said the Uighurs were moved through labour transfer schemes operating under a central government policy known as Xinjiang Aid.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The report said it was "extremely difficult" for Uighurs to refuse or escape the work assignments, with the threat of "arbitrary detention" hanging over them.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It added that there was evidence of local governments and private brokers being "paid a price per head" by the Xinjiang government to organise the assignments, which ASPI describes as "a new phase of the Chinese government's ongoing repression" of Uighurs.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/blogs-china-blog-48700786"&gt;
    Searching for truth in China's 're-education' camps
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-asia-china-51520622"&gt;
    Uighurs 'detained for beards and veils' - leak
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-asia-47157111"&gt;
    'I spent seven days of hell in Chinese camps'
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "Our report makes it really clear that the dispossession of Uighurs and other ethnic minorities in Xinjiang also has a really strong character of economic exploitation," the report's co-author Nathan Ruser told the BBC.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "We have this unseen and previously hidden contamination of the global supply chain."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Reports of widespread detentions at internment camps in Xinjiang first emerged in 2018. Chinese authorities said the "vocational training centres" were being used to combat violent religious extremism. But evidence showed many people were being detained for simply expressing their faith, by praying or wearing a veil, or for having overseas connections to places like Turkey.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-with-caption"&gt;
  &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder"&gt;
   &lt;img class="media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image narrative-video-placeholder" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p07gdrgp.jpg" /&gt;
   &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder__caption"&gt;
    Media playback is unsupported on your device
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder"&gt;
    &lt;div class="media-player-wrapper"&gt;
     &lt;figure class="js-media-player-unprocessed media-player"&gt;
     &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-with-caption__caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Media caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   The BBC's John Sudworth meets Uighur parents in Turkey who say their children are missing in China
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Beijing has faced growing international pressure over the issue.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Chinese state media says participation in labour transfer schemes is voluntary. Officials have denied any commercial use of forced labour from Xinjiang, according to ASPI.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  Where are they working?
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  ASPI said it had identified 27 factories in nine Chinese provinces that had been using Uighur labour transferred from Xinjiang since 2017.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It said the factories claim to be part of the supply chain for 83 well-known global brands, including Nike, Apple and Dell.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  At the factories, ASPI said the Uighurs were typically forced to live in segregated dormitories, have Mandarin lessons and "ideological training" outside of working hours, were subjected to constant surveillance and banned from observing religious practices.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-asia-china-50511063"&gt;
    Data leak details China's 'brainwashing system'
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/uk-50890519"&gt;
    Tesco Chinese card factory denies 'forced labour'
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  ASPI said foreign and Chinese companies were "possibly unknowingly" involved in human rights abuses. It called on them to conduct "immediate and thorough human rights due diligence" on their factory labour in China.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/asia_pacific/china-compels-uighurs-to-work-in-shoe-factory-that-supplies-nike/2020/02/28/ebddf5f4-57b2-11ea-8efd-0f904bdd8057_story.html"&gt;
   The Washington Post visited a factory mentioned in the report
  &lt;/a&gt;
  , which produces trainers for sports giant Nike. It said it resembled a prison, with barbed wire, watchtowers, cameras and a police station.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "We can walk around, but we can't go back [to Xinjiang] on our own," one Uighur woman told the newspaper at the gates of the factory in the city of Laixi.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Nike told the Washington Post it was "committed to upholding international labour standards globally" and that its suppliers were "strictly prohibited from using any type of prison, forced, bonded or indentured labor."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Apple also said it was "dedicated to ensuring that everyone in our supply chain is treated with the dignity and respect they deserve", while Dell said it would look into the findings.
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 18:03:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A visual guide to this outbreak</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-51235105</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="Man with a face mask in Hong Kong" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/03F9/production/_111071010_mask_man_getty_976.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  A fast-moving virus originating in China and known as the "new coronavirus" has infected tens of thousands of Chinese citizens and spread to more than 50 countries. It has claimed nearly 3,000 lives so far.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Here are 10 maps and charts that will help you understand what is going on.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  1. New infections outside China top those within
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Almost 80,000 people in China have been infected with the coronavirus - known officially as
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/q-a-coronaviruses"&gt;
   Covid-19
  &lt;/a&gt;
  - since the virus's discovery in the city of Wuhan, Hubei province, in December.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Although the vast majority of cases of the respiratory infection, which causes pneumonia-like symptoms, remain in China, the virus is now spreading faster outside the country than inside.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Coronavirus has infected more than 7,000 people across the rest of the globe, according to World Health Organization (WHO) figures.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  However, infectious disease specialists at Imperial College London estimate about two thirds of COVID-19 cases originating in mainland China
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/mrc-global-infectious-disease-analysis/news--wuhan-coronavirus/"&gt;
   remain undetected worldwide.
  &lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  This could mean "multiple chains of as yet undetected human-to-human transmission" internationally, they say.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The three biggest international outbreaks detected so far have been in South Korea, with more than 3,000 cases, on board the British-registered Diamond Princess cruise ship docked in Yokohama, Japan, which has seen more than 700 people infected, and Italy, with more than 1,000 confirmed cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In a sign the disease is spreading further afield, Mexico, Ecuador and Brazil have announced their first cases and the first cases in Africa have been confirmed in Algeria, Egypt and Nigeria. New Zealand has also confirmed its first case.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Within Europe, Austria, Croatia, Greece, Norway, Switzerland, Georgia and North Macedonia have reported their first cases, while more infections have been announced in Spain, France and Germany.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  On the Spanish island of Tenerife, up to 1,000 guests have been locked down in a hotel after an Italian doctor and his wife tested positive.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Governments across Europe are stepping up preparations, as more cases are detected.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  French President Emmanuel Macron has warned that a coronavirus epidemic in France is inevitable.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51048366"&gt;
    What are the symptoms?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51048366"&gt;
    How worried should we be?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  2. The virus has pandemic potential
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The jump in the number of daily confirmed cases internationally has raised fears the outbreak could become a pandemic - when an infectious disease spreads easily from person to person in many parts of the world.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The spread has reached a "decisive point" and has "pandemic potential", WHO head Dr Tedros Ghebreyesus says.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Dr Tedros urged governments to act swiftly to contain the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "This is not a time for fear," he said. "This is a time for taking action to prevent infection and save lives now."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Countries around the world are continuing to ramp up measures to battle the disease's spread.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Many have advised their citizens to avoid all non-essential travel to China and other affected countries, while others have announced screening measures for passengers arriving from places with outbreaks.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Stock markets around the world have
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51664652"&gt;
   fallen sharply
  &lt;/a&gt;
  amid fears that such increased travel restrictions will prevent business activity.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A number of international conferences and sporting events have also been cancelled, including Six Nations rugby matches with Italy in Dublin that were to be held on 7 and 8 March.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The US has declared the outbreak a public health emergency, the UK has deemed it a
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-51442314"&gt;
   "serious and imminent threat" to public health
  &lt;/a&gt;
  and Japan has closed all its schools.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The WHO declared the crisis a global health emergency on 30 January.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The organisation has confirmed it will not formally "declare" a pandemic for the new coronavirus, though the term may still be used "colloquially".
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51628753"&gt;
    How close are we to a pandemic?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  3. South Korea, Italy and Iran are among the worst-affected countries
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  South Korea, Italy and Iran have all seen significant outbreaks of cases in recent days, with South Korea the worst-affected country after China.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   South Korea
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  's biggest virus clusters have been linked to a religious group near the south-eastern city of Daegu, which has a population of around 2.5m.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Meanwhile in
  &lt;strong&gt;
   Italy
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  , the country's authorities have announced a series of measures to try to halt the virus's spread. It is not yet clear how it entered the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Eleven towns in northern Italy at the centre of the outbreak - home to a total of 55,000 people - have been quarantined. Schools, universities and cinemas have been closed and several public events cancelled.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The UK has advised against travelling to the region.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Several countries including Algeria, Denmark, Romania and Spain have reported infections linked to Italy.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   Iran
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  has seen almost 600 cases of the virus, most of them in the holy city of Qom, south of Tehran.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Iranian officials have asked people not to go to Qom, but have not shut a shrine in the city that attracts millions of Shia pilgrims each year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The government also said it had no plans to quarantine any cities and towns. despite fears of a regional epidemic.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Iran has been the source of dozens of cases in neighbouring countries, including Afghanistan, Bahrain, Iraq, Kuwait, Oman and Pakistan.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In response, many of Iran's neighbours have announced the temporary closure of their borders with the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Saudi Arabia has also
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51658061"&gt;
   temporarily banned pilgrims from entering the country
  &lt;/a&gt;
  to visit the holy sites of Mecca and Medina and suspended visas for tourists from countries with confirmed cases of the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-51645902"&gt;
    Coronavirus cases surge to 400 in Italy
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51658061"&gt;
    Saudi Arabia suspends entry for pilgrims
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  4. China still has by far the most cases
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The number of overall coronavirus cases in China has been rising since January.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The country accounts for almost 80,000 of the global 87,000 cases - and thousands more Chinese citizens are under medical observation.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Government and regional officials have introduced a number of tight restrictions in a bid to reduce infections, including cancelling flights, closing schools and workplaces and ordering some cities to go into lockdown.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Authorities also postponed the country's annual parliamentary gathering - the National People's Congress.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Hubei province - the centre of the outbreak - remains the worst affected, seeing by far the biggest number of cases of the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Its capital city of Wuhan, home to 11 million people, has been under lockdown since 23 January, with transport links into and out of the city closed.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The origins of the new coronavirus have been linked to illegally traded wildlife at Wuhan's seafood market, which sells live animals including bats, rabbits and marmots. However, the exact source of the outbreak has not been identified.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Hundreds of foreign nationals have been evacuated from Wuhan by several governments including the US, France and Britain.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-51628693"&gt;
    How China is keeping busy during quarantine
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  5. Daily infections and deaths in China have been comparatively low recently
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  New cases announced in China have remained low over recent days, compared with numbers seen in early-mid February, according to official figures.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Figures have stayed in the hundreds rather than the thousands for the last week, following a spike in mid-February.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Officials in Hubei province have come under fire for their handling of the virus outbreak, including causing confusion by changing the criteria used to count the number of cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Changes to the way patients were diagnosed half way through February caused a brief spike in the number of confirmed cases, but this change was later reversed, causing a later dip.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The number of deaths announced each day by the Chinese authorities have been dropping for most of the last few days. Like the daily confirmed cases, daily death figures saw a spike caused by the change in diagnosis criteria in mid-February.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Wuhan continues to account for the majority of new cases and deaths in China.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Despite the drop in deaths, the new coronavirus has overtaken the 2003 Sars epidemic in both confirmed cases and deaths.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The Sars - severe acute respiratory syndrome - outbreak lasted around eight months and killed 774 people out of around 8,100 confirmed cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-51235105"&gt;
   Coronavirus: A visual guide to the outbreak
  &lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A study of 44,000 coronavirus cases by the Chinese Centre for Disease Control and Prevention found that more than 80% had been mild, with the sick and elderly most at risk, while 4.7% had been critical.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A report on the early stages of the outbreak by the Lancet medical journal said most patients who died from the virus had had pre-existing conditions.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Medical researchers and scientists say it is too early to accurately predict how the virus will spread or calculate the death rate, partly due to mild cases remaining untested and unrecorded and a time lag of reporting infections.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As there is not yet a specific anti-viral treatment for coronavirus, people with the infection are currently being treated for their symptoms.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;
   By Lucy Rodgers, Mike Hills, Dominic Bailey and Wesley Stephenson
  &lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 17:44:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coronavirus: What are the chances of dying?</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51674743</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="Two medical workers put on protective clothing at a hospital to treat coronavirus patients in Wuhan, China." class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/4873/production/_111074581_gettyimages-1203459555.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    More than 50 countries have now confirmed cases
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  Researchers currently think that between five and 40 coronavirus cases in 1,000 will result in death, with a best guess of nine in 1,000 or about 1%.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  On Sunday, Health Secretary Matt Hancock said the UK government's "very best assessment" was that the mortality rate was "2% or, likely, lower".
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But it depends on a range of factors: your age, sex and general health and the health system you are in.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  How hard is it to work out the death rate?
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It is PhD-level hard. Even counting cases is tricky.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Most cases of most viruses will go uncounted because people tend not to visit the doctor with mild symptoms.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The different death rates we are seeing reported around the world are unlikely to be due to different versions of the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/media/imperial-college/medicine/sph/ide/gida-fellowships/Imperial-College-2019-nCoV-severity-10-02-2020.pdf"&gt;
   According to research by Imperial College
  &lt;/a&gt;
  , it's because different countries are better or worse at spotting the milder, harder to count cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  So under-reporting cases makes it easy to overestimate the death rate. But you can also get it wrong in the other direction.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It takes time before an infection results in recovery or death.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  If you include all cases that haven't yet had a chance to run their course, you will underestimate the death rate because you are missing the cases that will end in death later.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51048366"&gt;
    Coronavirus: All you need to know
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-51235105"&gt;
    A visual guide to the outbreak
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Scientists combine individual pieces of evidence about each of these questions to build a picture of the death rate.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  For example, they estimate the proportion of cases with mild symptoms from small, defined groups of people who are monitored very tightly, like people on repatriated flights.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But slightly different answers from those pieces of evidence will add up to big changes in the overall picture.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  If you just use data from Hubei, where the death rate has been much higher than elsewhere in China, then the overall death rate will look much worse.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  So scientists give a range as well as a best current estimate.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But even that doesn't tell the full story because there is no single death rate.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/explainers-51632801"&gt;
    How is the UK getting ready for coronavirus?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  What's the risk for people like me?
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Some types of people are more likely to die if they contract coronavirus: the elderly, the unwell and, maybe, men.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In the first big
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-51540981"&gt;
   analysis of more than 44,000 cases from China
  &lt;/a&gt;
  , the death rate was ten times higher in the very elderly compared to the middle-aged.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The death rates were lowest for the under 30s - there were eight deaths in 4,500 cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  And deaths were at least five times more common among people with diabetes, high blood pressure or heart or breathing problems.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  There was even a slightly higher number of deaths among men compared to women.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  All of these factors interact with each other and we don't yet have a complete picture of the risk for every type of person in every location.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    At least 621 people were infected on the Diamond Princess cruise ship in Japan
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  What's the risk for people where I live?
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A group of 80-year-old men in China could have very different risks to men of the same age in Europe or Africa.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Your prognosis also depends on the treatment you get.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In turn, that depends on what is available and the stage of the epidemic.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  If the epidemic takes off, then healthcare systems could get swamped with cases - there are only so many intensive care units or ventilators available in any given area.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    Coronavirus patients in England are being treated at a specialist centre at the Royal Free Hospital in London
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  Is it more dangerous than flu?
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  We can't compare mortality rates because many people with mild flu symptoms choose never to visit a doctor.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  So we don't know how many cases there are of flu, or any new virus every year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But flu continues to kill people in the UK, as it does every winter.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As the data evolves, scientists will develop a clearer picture of who would be most at risk should a coronavirus outbreak arrive in the UK.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The basic advice from the WHO is that you can protect yourself from all respiratory viruses by washing your hands, avoiding people who are coughing and sneezing and trying not to touch your eyes, nose and mouth.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-51674696"&gt;
    What is the coronavirus advice in the UK?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;hr class="story-body__line" /&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   Have you been affected by the coronavirus? Or do you have any information to share? Get in touch by emailing
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-email" href="mailto:haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk?subject=Coronavirus51673068"&gt;
   &lt;span class="icon email"&gt;
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-body__link-email-text"&gt;
    haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   .
  &lt;/strong&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Please include a contact number if you are willing to speak to a BBC journalist. You can also contact us in the following ways:
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   WhatsApp:
   &lt;strong&gt;
    +44 7756 165803
   &lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   Tweet:
   &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="http://twitter.com/BBC_HaveYourSay"&gt;
    @BBC_HaveYourSay
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   Send pictures/video to
   &lt;a class="story-body__link-email" href="mailto:yourpics@bbc.co.uk"&gt;
    &lt;span class="icon email"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="story-body__link-email-text"&gt;
     yourpics@bbc.co.uk
    &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/send/u16904890"&gt;
    Upload your pictures / video here
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   Please read our
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/usingthebbc/terms/"&gt;
    terms &amp;amp; conditions
   &lt;/a&gt;
   and
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/usingthebbc/privacy-policy/"&gt;
    privacy policy
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  ,
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 13:21:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A visual guide to this outbreak</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-51235105</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="Man with a face mask in Hong Kong" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/03F9/production/_111071010_mask_man_getty_976.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  A fast-moving virus originating in China and known as the "new coronavirus" has infected tens of thousands of Chinese citizens and spread to more than 50 countries. It has claimed nearly 3,000 lives so far.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Here are 10 maps and charts that will help you understand what is going on.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  1. New infections outside China top those within
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Almost 80,000 people in China have been infected with the coronavirus - known officially as
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/q-a-coronaviruses"&gt;
   Covid-19
  &lt;/a&gt;
  - since the virus's discovery in the city of Wuhan, Hubei province, in December.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Although the vast majority of cases of the respiratory infection, which causes pneumonia-like symptoms, remain in China, the virus is now spreading faster outside the country than inside.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Coronavirus has infected more than 6,000 people across the rest of the globe, according to World Health Organization (WHO) figures.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  However, infectious disease specialists at Imperial College London estimate about two thirds of COVID-19 cases originating in mainland China
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/mrc-global-infectious-disease-analysis/news--wuhan-coronavirus/"&gt;
   remain undetected worldwide.
  &lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  This could mean "multiple chains of as yet undetected human-to-human transmission" internationally, they say.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The three biggest international outbreaks detected so far have been in South Korea, with more than 3,000 cases, on board the British-registered Diamond Princess cruise ship docked in Yokohama, Japan, which has seen more than 700 people infected, and Italy, with more than 1,000 confirmed cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In a sign the disease is spreading further afield, Mexico, Ecuador and Brazil have announced their first cases and the first cases in Africa have been confirmed in Algeria, Egypt and Nigeria. New Zealand has also confirmed its first case.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Within Europe, Austria, Croatia, Greece, Norway, Switzerland, Georgia and North Macedonia have reported their first cases, while more infections have been announced in Spain, France and Germany.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  On the Spanish island of Tenerife, up to 1,000 guests have been locked down in a hotel after an Italian doctor and his wife tested positive.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Governments across Europe are stepping up preparations, as more cases are detected.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  French President Emmanuel Macron has warned that a coronavirus epidemic in France is inevitable.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51048366"&gt;
    What are the symptoms?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51048366"&gt;
    How worried should we be?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  2. The virus has pandemic potential
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The jump in the number of daily confirmed cases internationally has raised fears the outbreak could become a pandemic - when an infectious disease spreads easily from person to person in many parts of the world.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The spread has reached a "decisive point" and has "pandemic potential", WHO head Dr Tedros Ghebreyesus says.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Dr Tedros urged governments to act swiftly to contain the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "This is not a time for fear," he said. "This is a time for taking action to prevent infection and save lives now."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Countries around the world are continuing to ramp up measures to battle the disease's spread.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Many have advised their citizens to avoid all non-essential travel to China and other affected countries, while others have announced screening measures for passengers arriving from places with outbreaks.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Stock markets around the world have
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51664652"&gt;
   fallen sharply
  &lt;/a&gt;
  amid fears that such increased travel restrictions will prevent business activity.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A number of international conferences and sporting events have also been cancelled, including Six Nations rugby matches with Italy in Dublin that were to be held on 7 and 8 March.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The US has declared the outbreak a public health emergency, the UK has deemed it a
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-51442314"&gt;
   "serious and imminent threat" to public health
  &lt;/a&gt;
  and Japan has closed all its schools.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The WHO declared the crisis a global health emergency on 30 January.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The organisation has confirmed it will not formally "declare" a pandemic for the new coronavirus, though the term may still be used "colloquially".
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51628753"&gt;
    How close are we to a pandemic?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  3. South Korea, Italy and Iran are among the worst-affected countries
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  South Korea, Italy and Iran have all seen significant outbreaks of cases in recent days, with South Korea the worst-affected country after China.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   South Korea
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  's biggest virus clusters have been linked to a religious group near the south-eastern city of Daegu, which has a population of around 2.5m.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Meanwhile in
  &lt;strong&gt;
   Italy
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  , the country's authorities have announced a series of measures to try to halt the virus's spread. It is not yet clear how it entered the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Eleven towns in northern Italy at the centre of the outbreak - home to a total of 55,000 people - have been quarantined. Schools, universities and cinemas have been closed and several public events cancelled.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The UK has advised against travelling to the region.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Several countries including Algeria, Denmark, Romania and Spain have reported infections linked to Italy.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   Iran
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  has seen almost 600 cases of the virus, most of them in the holy city of Qom, south of Tehran.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Iranian officials have asked people not to go to Qom, but have not shut a shrine in the city that attracts millions of Shia pilgrims each year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The government also said it had no plans to quarantine any cities and towns. despite fears of a regional epidemic.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Iran has been the source of dozens of cases in neighbouring countries, including Afghanistan, Bahrain, Iraq, Kuwait, Oman and Pakistan.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In response, many of Iran's neighbours have announced the temporary closure of their borders with the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Saudi Arabia has also
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51658061"&gt;
   temporarily banned pilgrims from entering the country
  &lt;/a&gt;
  to visit the holy sites of Mecca and Medina and suspended visas for tourists from countries with confirmed cases of the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-51645902"&gt;
    Coronavirus cases surge to 400 in Italy
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51658061"&gt;
    Saudi Arabia suspends entry for pilgrims
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  4. China still has by far the most cases
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The number of overall coronavirus cases in China has been rising since January.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The country accounts for almost 80,000 of the global 87,000 cases - and thousands more Chinese citizens are under medical observation.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Government and regional officials have introduced a number of tight restrictions in a bid to reduce infections, including cancelling flights, closing schools and workplaces and ordering some cities to go into lockdown.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Authorities also postponed the country's annual parliamentary gathering - the National People's Congress.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Hubei province - the centre of the outbreak - remains the worst affected, seeing by far the biggest number of cases of the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Its capital city of Wuhan, home to 11 million people, has been under lockdown since 23 January, with transport links into and out of the city closed.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The origins of the new coronavirus have been linked to illegally traded wildlife at Wuhan's seafood market, which sells live animals including bats, rabbits and marmots. However, the exact source of the outbreak has not been identified.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Hundreds of foreign nationals have been evacuated from Wuhan by several governments including the US, France and Britain.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-51628693"&gt;
    How China is keeping busy during quarantine
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  5. Daily infections and deaths in China have been comparatively low recently
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  New cases announced in China have remained low over recent days, compared with numbers seen in early-mid February, according to official figures.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Figures have stayed in the hundreds rather than the thousands for the last week, following a spike in mid-February.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Officials in Hubei province have come under fire for their handling of the virus outbreak, including causing confusion by changing the criteria used to count the number of cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Changes to the way patients were diagnosed half way through February caused a brief spike in the number of confirmed cases, but this change was later reversed, causing a later dip.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The number of deaths announced each day by the Chinese authorities have been dropping for most of the last few days. Like the daily confirmed cases, daily death figures saw a spike caused by the change in diagnosis criteria in mid-February.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Wuhan continues to account for the majority of new cases and deaths in China.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Despite the drop in deaths, the new coronavirus has overtaken the 2003 Sars epidemic in both confirmed cases and deaths.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The Sars - severe acute respiratory syndrome - outbreak lasted around eight months and killed 774 people out of around 8,100 confirmed cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-51235105"&gt;
   Coronavirus: A visual guide to the outbreak
  &lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A study of 44,000 coronavirus cases by the Chinese Centre for Disease Control and Prevention found that more than 80% had been mild, with the sick and elderly most at risk, while 4.7% had been critical.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A report on the early stages of the outbreak by the Lancet medical journal said most patients who died from the virus had had pre-existing conditions.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Medical researchers and scientists say it is too early to accurately predict how the virus will spread or calculate the death rate, partly due to mild cases remaining untested and unrecorded and a time lag of reporting infections.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As there is not yet a specific anti-viral treatment for coronavirus, people with the infection are currently being treated for their symptoms.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;
   By Lucy Rodgers, Mike Hills, Dominic Bailey and Wesley Stephenson
  &lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 10:59:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coronavirus: Nasa images show China pollution clear amid slowdown</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-51691967</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="A map released by Nasa shows how air pollution levels have reduced in China this year" class="js-image-replace" height="545" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/155CA/production/_111089478_china_trop_2020056.png" width="720" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    NASA
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="Presentational white space" class="js-image-replace" height="1" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/94C2/production/_109028083_1px_white_line-nc.png" width="624" /&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  Satellite images have shown a dramatic decline in pollution levels over China, which is "at least partly" due to an economic slowdown prompted by the coronavirus, US space agency Nasa says.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Nasa maps show how levels of nitrogen dioxide have fallen this year, and compared to the same period in 2019.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It comes amid record declines in China's factory activity as manufacturers stop work in a bid to contain the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  China has nearly 80,000 cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The virus has spread to more than 50 countries but the vast majority of infections and deaths are in China, where the virus originated late last year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/business-51689178"&gt;
    Coronavirus spread hits Chinese manufacturing
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-asia-china-51276656"&gt;
    Diary of a life in locked-down Wuhan
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/health-51674743"&gt;
    How deadly is the coronavirus?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Nasa scientists said the reduction in levels of nitrogen dioxide - a noxious gas emitted by motor vehicles and industrial facilities - was first apparent near the source of the outbreak in Wuhan city but then spread across the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    NASA
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The space agency noted that the decline in air pollution levels coincided with restriction imposed on transportation and business activities, and as millions of people went into quarantine.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "This is the first time I have seen such a dramatic drop-off over such a wide area for a specific event," Fei Liu, an air quality researcher at Nasa's Goddard Space Flight Center, said in a statement.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  She added that she had observed a decline in nitrogen dioxide levels during the economic recession in 2008, but said that decrease was more gradual.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Nasa noted that China's Lunar New Year celebrations in late January and early February have been linked to decreases in pollution levels in the past. But it said they normally increase once the celebrations are over.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "This year, the reduction rate is more significant than in past years and it has lasted longer," Ms Liu said.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "I am not surprised because many cities nationwide have taken measures to minimise spread of the virus."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  You might be interested in watching:
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-with-caption"&gt;
  &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder"&gt;
   &lt;img class="media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image narrative-video-placeholder" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p084zp0v.jpg" /&gt;
   &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder__caption"&gt;
    Media playback is unsupported on your device
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder"&gt;
    &lt;div class="media-player-wrapper"&gt;
     &lt;figure class="js-media-player-unprocessed media-player"&gt;
     &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-with-caption__caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Media caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   Coronavirus: The ‘propaganda push’ in China
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 18:41:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A visual guide to this outbreak</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-51235105</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="Man with a face mask in Hong Kong" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/03F9/production/_111071010_mask_man_getty_976.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  A fast-moving virus originating in China and known as the "new coronavirus" has infected tens of thousands of Chinese citizens and spread to more than 50 countries. It has claimed nearly 3,000 lives so far.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Here are 11 maps and charts that will help you understand what is going on.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  1. New infections outside China top those within
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Almost 80,000 people in China have been infected with the coronavirus - known officially as
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/q-a-coronaviruses"&gt;
   Covid-19
  &lt;/a&gt;
  - since the virus's discovery in the city of Wuhan, Hubei province, in December.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Although the vast majority of cases of the respiratory infection, which causes pneumonia-like symptoms, remain in China, the virus is now spreading faster outside the country than inside.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Coronavirus has infected more than 6,000 people across the rest of the globe, according to World Health Organization (WHO) figures.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  However, infectious disease specialists at Imperial College London estimate about two thirds of COVID-19 cases originating in mainland China
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/mrc-global-infectious-disease-analysis/news--wuhan-coronavirus/"&gt;
   remain undetected worldwide.
  &lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  This could mean "multiple chains of as yet undetected human-to-human transmission" internationally, they say.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The three biggest international outbreaks detected so far have been in South Korea, with more than 3,000 cases, on board the British-registered Diamond Princess cruise ship docked in Yokohama, Japan, which has seen more than 700 people infected, and Italy, with more than 850 confirmed cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In a sign the disease is spreading further afield, Brazil announced Latin America's first case on Thursday and the first cases in Africa have been confirmed in Algeria, Egypt and Nigeria. New Zealand has also confirmed its first case.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Within Europe, Austria, Croatia, Greece, Norway, Switzerland, Georgia and North Macedonia have reported their first cases, while more infections have been announced in Spain, France and Germany.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  On the Spanish island of Tenerife, up to 1,000 guests have been locked down in a hotel after an Italian doctor and his wife tested positive.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Governments across Europe are stepping up preparations, as more cases are detected.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  French President Emmanuel Macron has warned that a coronavirus epidemic in France is inevitable.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51048366"&gt;
    What are the symptoms?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51048366"&gt;
    How worried should we be?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  2. The virus has pandemic potential
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The jump in the number of daily confirmed cases internationally has raised fears the outbreak could become a pandemic - when an infectious disease spreads easily from person to person in many parts of the world.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The spread has reached a "decisive point" and has "pandemic potential", WHO head Dr Tedros Ghebreyesus says.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Dr Tedros urged governments to act swiftly to contain the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "This is not a time for fear," he said. "This is a time for taking action to prevent infection and save lives now."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Countries around the world are continuing to ramp up measures to battle the disease's spread.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Many have advised their citizens to avoid all non-essential travel to China and other affected countries, while others have announced screening measures for passengers arriving from places with outbreaks.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Stock markets around the world have
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51664652"&gt;
   fallen sharply
  &lt;/a&gt;
  amid fears that such increased travel restrictions will prevent business activity.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A number of international conferences and sporting events have also been cancelled, including Six Nations rugby matches with Italy in Dublin that were to be held on 7 and 8 March.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The US has declared the outbreak a public health emergency, the UK has deemed it a
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-51442314"&gt;
   "serious and imminent threat" to public health
  &lt;/a&gt;
  and Japan has closed all its schools.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The WHO declared the crisis a global health emergency on 30 January.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The organisation has confirmed it will not formally "declare" a pandemic for the new coronavirus, though the term may still be used "colloquially".
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51628753"&gt;
    How close are we to a pandemic?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  3. South Korea, Italy and Iran are among the worst-affected countries
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  South Korea, Italy and Iran have all seen significant outbreaks of cases in recent days, with South Korea the worst-affected country after China.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   South Korea
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  's biggest virus clusters have been linked to a religious group near the south-eastern city of Daegu, which has a population of around 2.5m.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Meanwhile in
  &lt;strong&gt;
   Italy
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  , the country's authorities have announced a series of measures to try to halt the virus's spread. It is not yet clear how it entered the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Eleven towns in northern Italy at the centre of the outbreak - home to a total of 55,000 people - have been quarantined. Schools, universities and cinemas have been closed and several public events cancelled.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The UK has advised against travelling to the region.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Several countries including Algeria, Denmark, Romania and Spain have reported infections linked to Italy.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   Iran
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  confirmed it has seen a number of cases of the virus, most of them in the holy city of Qom, south of Tehran.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Iranian officials have asked people not to go to Qom, but have not shut a shrine in the city that attracts millions of Shia pilgrims each year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The government also said it had no plans to quarantine any cities and towns. despite fears of a regional epidemic.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;
   Note: Map based on Iran's Ministry of Health figures, given on state TV, which may differ from WHO numbers
  &lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Iran has been the source of dozens of cases in neighbouring countries, including Afghanistan, Bahrain, Iraq, Kuwait, Oman and Pakistan.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In response, many of Iran's neighbours have announced the temporary closure of their borders with the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Saudi Arabia has also
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51658061"&gt;
   temporarily banned pilgrims from entering the country
  &lt;/a&gt;
  to visit the holy sites of Mecca and Medina and suspended visas for tourists from countries with confirmed cases of the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-51645902"&gt;
    Coronavirus cases surge to 400 in Italy
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51658061"&gt;
    Saudi Arabia suspends entry for pilgrims
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  4. China still has by far the most cases
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The number of overall coronavirus cases in China has been rising since January.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The country accounts for more than 79,000 of the global 85,000 cases - and thousands more Chinese citizens are under medical observation.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Government and regional officials have introduced a number of tight restrictions in a bid to reduce infections, including cancelling flights, closing schools and workplaces and ordering some cities to go into lockdown.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Authorities also postponed the country's annual parliamentary gathering - the National People's Congress.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Hubei province - the centre of the outbreak - remains the worst affected, seeing by far the biggest number of cases of the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Its capital city of Wuhan, home to 11 million people, has been under lockdown since 23 January, with transport links into and out of the city closed.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The origins of the new coronavirus have been linked to illegally traded wildlife at Wuhan's seafood market, which sells live animals including bats, rabbits and marmots. However, the exact source of the outbreak has not been identified.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Hundreds of foreign nationals have been evacuated from Wuhan by several governments including the US, France and Britain.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-51628693"&gt;
    How China is keeping busy during quarantine
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  5. Daily infections and deaths in China have been comparatively low recently
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  New cases announced in China have remained low over recent days, compared with numbers seen in early-mid February, according to official figures.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Figures have stayed in the hundreds rather than the thousands for the last week, following a spike in mid-February.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Officials in Hubei province have come under fire for their handling of the virus outbreak, including causing confusion by changing the criteria used to count the number of cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Changes to the way patients were diagnosed half way through February caused a brief spike in the number of confirmed cases, but this change was later reversed, causing a later dip.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The number of deaths announced each day by the Chinese authorities have been dropping for most of the last few days. Like the daily confirmed cases, daily death figures saw a spike caused by the change in diagnosis criteria in mid-February.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Wuhan continues to account for the majority of new cases and deaths in China.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Despite the drop in deaths, the new coronavirus has overtaken the 2003 Sars epidemic in both confirmed cases and deaths.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The Sars - severe acute respiratory syndrome - outbreak lasted around eight months and killed 774 people out of around 8,100 confirmed cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A study of 44,000 coronavirus cases by the Chinese Centre for Disease Control and Prevention found that more than 80% had been mild, with the sick and elderly most at risk, while 4.7% had been critical.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A report on the early stages of the outbreak by the Lancet medical journal said most patients who died from the virus had had pre-existing conditions.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Medical researchers and scientists say it is too early to accurately predict how the virus will spread or calculate the death rate, partly due to mild cases remaining untested and unrecorded and a time lag of reporting infections.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As there is not yet a specific anti-viral treatment for coronavirus, people with the infection are currently being treated for their symptoms.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;
   By Lucy Rodgers, Mike Hills, Dominic Bailey and Wesley Stephenson
  &lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 18:25:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese manufacturing hits record low amid coronavirus outbreak</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51689178</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="Workers wearing face masks as they make insoles at a factory" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/1368/production/_111086940_hi060291106.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    AFP
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    Economic data shows the virus is hitting Chinese factories harder than the 2008 financial crisis
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  Factory activity in China fell at a record rate in February, as manufacturers closed their operations to contain the spread of coronavirus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The country's official measure of manufacturing activity - the Purchasing Manager's Index (PMI) - dropped to 35.7 from 50 in January.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It shows the virus is having a bigger impact than the financial crisis that shook the world last decade.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The data also suggests that factories are struggling to find enough workers.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  PMI figures - calculated with data from monthly surveys of private sector companies - are a key indicator of a county's economic health, and can move financial markets.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  China makes up a third of world manufacturing and is the world's largest exporter, so this PMI drop - well below analysts' expectations - will have a knock-on effect on other countries.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51639654"&gt;
    US markets suffer worst week since 2008's global financial crisis
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/business-51676600"&gt;
    Why should I care if share prices fall?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Restrictions in place in the so-called "factory of the world" have also affected companies such as Apple, Diageo, Jaguar Land Rover and Volkswagen, which rely on China's production and consumer market.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The big question now is how quickly factories can return to normal.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Many are dependent on China's 300 million migrant workers, a third of whom are still not working because of quarantine rules.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  According to Bloomberg Economics, Chinese factories were operating at 60% to 70% of capacity this week.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It is expected that China's economic growth will take a significant hit in the first half of this year because of the impact coronavirus has had on business and spending in the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Stock markets around the world fell dramatically this week after a surge in the number of companies warning about the impact of the outbreak on firms.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  There was one silver lining to the fall in Chinese output though: Nasa said pollution monitoring satellites had detected significant decreases in nitrogen dioxide over the country, which evidence suggests is "at least partly" related to the economic slowdown caused by the outbreak.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    NASA
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 17:27:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese manufacturing hits record low amid coronavirus outbreak</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51689178</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="Workers wearing face masks as they make insoles at a factory" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/1368/production/_111086940_hi060291106.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    AFP
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    Economic data shows the virus is hitting Chinese factories harder than the 2008 financial crisis
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  Factory activity in China fell at a record rate in February, as manufacturers closed their operations to contain the spread of coronavirus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The country's official measure of manufacturing activity - the Purchasing Manager's Index (PMI) - dropped to 35.7 from 50 in January.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It shows the virus is having a bigger impact than the financial crisis that shook the world last decade.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The data also suggests that factories are struggling to find enough workers.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  PMI figures - calculated with data from monthly surveys of private sector companies - are a key indicator of a county's economic health, and can move financial markets.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  China makes up a third of world manufacturing and is the world's largest exporter, so this PMI drop - well below analysts' expectations - will have a knock-on effect on other countries.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51639654"&gt;
    US markets suffer worst week since 2008's global financial crisis
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/business-51676600"&gt;
    Why should I care if share prices fall?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Restrictions in place in the so-called "factory of the world" have also affected companies such as Apple, Diageo, Jaguar Land Rover and Volkswagen, which rely on China's production and consumer market.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The big question now is how quickly factories can return to normal.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Many are dependent on China's 300 million migrant workers, a third of whom are still not working because of quarantine rules.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  According to Bloomberg Economics, Chinese factories were operating at 60% to 70% of capacity this week.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It is expected that China's economic growth will take a significant hit in the first half of this year because of the impact coronavirus has had on business and spending in the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Stock markets around the world fell dramatically this week after a surge in the number of companies warning about the impact of the outbreak on firms.
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 13:36:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A visual guide to this outbreak</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-51235105</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="Man with a face mask in Hong Kong" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/03F9/production/_111071010_mask_man_getty_976.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  A fast-moving virus originating in China and known as the "new coronavirus" has infected tens of thousands of Chinese citizens and spread to more than 50 countries. It has claimed nearly 3,000 lives so far.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Here are 11 maps and charts that will help you understand what is going on.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  1. New infections outside China top those within
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Almost 80,000 people in China have been infected with the coronavirus - known officially as
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/q-a-coronaviruses"&gt;
   Covid-19
  &lt;/a&gt;
  - since the virus's discovery in the city of Wuhan, Hubei province, in December.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Although the vast majority of cases of the respiratory infection, which causes pneumonia-like symptoms, remain in China, the virus is now spreading faster outside the country than inside.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Coronavirus has infected more than 4,500 people across the globe, according to World Health Organization (WHO) figures.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  However, infectious disease specialists at Imperial College London estimate about two thirds of COVID-19 cases originating in mainland China
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/mrc-global-infectious-disease-analysis/news--wuhan-coronavirus/"&gt;
   remain undetected worldwide.
  &lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  This could mean "multiple chains of as yet undetected human-to-human transmission" internationally, they say.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The three biggest international outbreaks detected so far have been in South Korea, with more than 2,300 cases, on board the British-registered Diamond Princess cruise ship docked in Yokohama, Japan, which has seen more than 700 people infected, and Italy, with more than 640 confirmed cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In a sign the disease is spreading further afield, Brazil announced Latin America's first case on Thursday and the first cases in Africa have been confirmed in Algeria, Egypt and Nigeria. New Zealand has also confirmed its first case.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Within Europe, Austria, Croatia, Greece, Norway, Switzerland, Georgia and North Macedonia have reported their first cases, while more infections have been announced in Spain, France and Germany.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  On the Spanish island of Tenerife, up to 1,000 guests have been locked down in a hotel after an Italian doctor and his wife tested positive.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Governments across Europe are stepping up preparations, as more cases are detected.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  French President Emmanuel Macron has warned that a coronavirus epidemic in France is inevitable.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51048366"&gt;
    What are the symptoms?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51048366"&gt;
    How worried should we be?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  2. The virus has pandemic potential
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The jump in the number of daily confirmed cases internationally has raised fears the outbreak could become a pandemic - when an infectious disease spreads easily from person to person in many parts of the world.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The spread has reached a "decisive point" and has "pandemic potential", WHO head Dr Tedros Ghebreyesus says.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Dr Tedros urged governments to act swiftly to contain the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "This is not a time for fear," he said. "This is a time for taking action to prevent infection and save lives now."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Countries around the world are continuing to ramp up measures to battle the disease's spread.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Many have advised their citizens to avoid all non-essential travel to China and other affected countries, while others have announced screening measures for passengers arriving from places with outbreaks.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Stock markets around the world have
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51664652"&gt;
   fallen sharply
  &lt;/a&gt;
  amid fears that such increased travel restrictions will prevent business activity.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A number of international conferences and sporting events have also been cancelled, including Six Nations rugby matches with Italy in Dublin that were to be held on 7 and 8 March.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The US has declared the outbreak a public health emergency, the UK has deemed it a
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-51442314"&gt;
   "serious and imminent threat" to public health
  &lt;/a&gt;
  and Japan has closed all its schools.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The WHO declared the crisis a global health emergency on 30 January.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The organisation has confirmed it will not formally "declare" a pandemic for the new coronavirus, though the term may still be used "colloquially".
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51628753"&gt;
    How close are we to a pandemic?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  3. South Korea, Italy and Iran are among the worst-affected countries
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  South Korea, Italy and Iran have all seen significant outbreaks of cases in recent days, with South Korea the worst-affected country after China.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   South Korea
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  's biggest virus clusters have been linked to a religious group near the south-eastern city of Daegu, which has a population of around 2.5m.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Meanwhile in
  &lt;strong&gt;
   Italy
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  , the country's authorities have announced a series of measures to try to halt the virus's spread. It is not yet clear how it entered the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Eleven towns in northern Italy at the centre of the outbreak - home to a total of 55,000 people - have been quarantined. Schools, universities and cinemas have been closed and several public events cancelled.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The UK has advised against travelling to the region.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Several countries including Algeria, Denmark, Romania and Spain have reported infections linked to Italy.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   Iran
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  confirmed it has seen a number of cases of the virus, most of them in the holy city of Qom, south of Tehran.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Iranian officials have asked people not to go to Qom, but have not shut a shrine in the city that attracts millions of Shia pilgrims each year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The government also said it had no plans to quarantine any cities and towns. despite fears of a regional epidemic.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;
   Note: Map based on Iran's Ministry of Health figures, given on state TV, which may differ from WHO numbers
  &lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Iran has been the source of dozens of cases in neighbouring countries, including Afghanistan, Bahrain, Iraq, Kuwait, Oman and Pakistan.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In response, many of Iran's neighbours have announced the temporary closure of their borders with the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Saudi Arabia has also
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51658061"&gt;
   temporarily banned pilgrims from entering the country
  &lt;/a&gt;
  to visit the holy sites of Mecca and Medina and suspended visas for tourists from countries with confirmed cases of the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-51645902"&gt;
    Coronavirus cases surge to 400 in Italy
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51658061"&gt;
    Saudi Arabia suspends entry for pilgrims
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  4. China still has by far the most cases
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The number of overall coronavirus cases in China has been rising since January.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The country accounts for almost 79,000 of the global 83,000 cases - and thousands more Chinese citizens are under medical observation.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Government and regional officials have introduced a number of tight restrictions in a bid to reduce infections, including cancelling flights, closing schools and workplaces and ordering some cities to go into lockdown.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Authorities also postponed the country's annual parliamentary gathering - the National People's Congress.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Hubei province - the centre of the outbreak - remains the worst affected, seeing by far the biggest number of cases of the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Its capital city of Wuhan, home to 11 million people, has been under lockdown since 23 January, with transport links into and out of the city closed.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The origins of the new coronavirus have been linked to illegally traded wildlife at Wuhan's seafood market, which sells live animals including bats, rabbits and marmots. However, the exact source of the outbreak has not been identified.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Hundreds of foreign nationals have been evacuated from Wuhan by several governments including the US, France and Britain.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-51628693"&gt;
    How China is keeping busy during quarantine
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  5. Daily infections and deaths in China have been comparatively low recently
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  New cases announced in China have remained low over recent days, compared with numbers seen in early-mid February, according to official figures.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Figures have stayed in the hundreds rather than the thousands for the last week, following a spike in mid-February.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Officials in Hubei province have come under fire for their handling of the virus outbreak, including causing confusion by changing the criteria used to count the number of cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Changes to the way patients were diagnosed half way through February caused a brief spike in the number of confirmed cases, but this change was later reversed, causing a later dip.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The number of deaths announced each day by the Chinese authorities have been dropping for most of the last few days. Like the daily confirmed cases, daily death figures saw a spike caused by the change in diagnosis criteria in mid-February.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Wuhan continues to account for the majority of new cases and deaths in China.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Despite the drop in deaths, the new coronavirus has overtaken the 2003 Sars epidemic in both confirmed cases and deaths.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The Sars - severe acute respiratory syndrome - outbreak lasted around eight months and killed 774 people out of around 8,100 confirmed cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A study of 44,000 coronavirus cases by the Chinese Centre for Disease Control and Prevention found that more than 80% had been mild, with the sick and elderly most at risk, while 4.7% had been critical.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A report on the early stages of the outbreak by the Lancet medical journal said most patients who died from the virus had had pre-existing conditions.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Medical researchers and scientists say it is too early to accurately predict how the virus will spread or calculate the death rate, partly due to mild cases remaining untested and unrecorded and a time lag of reporting infections.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As there is not yet a specific anti-viral treatment for coronavirus, people with the infection are currently being treated for their symptoms.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;
   By Lucy Rodgers, Mike Hills, Dominic Bailey and Wesley Stephenson
  &lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 10:52:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coronavirus: Misinformation and false medical advice spreads in Iran</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51677530</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="Tehran Municipality workers clean a metro train to avoid the spread of the COVID-19 illness on February 26, 2020." class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/12A4F/production/_111076367_topimage.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    AFP/GETTY IMAGES
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  Iran has been scrambling to control the outbreak of the coronavirus this week, but the spread of online misinformation is presenting a new challenge to the authorities.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  False or misleading medical advice, fake letters or remarks attributed to senior officials, and a number of conspiracy theories about the origin of the virus have appeared on Iranian social media and messaging apps in recent days.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Officials have so far reported
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51673053"&gt;
   388 confirmed Covid-19 cases and 34 related deaths in the country
  &lt;/a&gt;
  , more fatalities than anywhere else outside China.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But sources in the country's health system have told BBC Persian that
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51673053"&gt;
   the death toll currently stands at 210
  &lt;/a&gt;
  .
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  According to Cyber Police Chief Vahid Majid,
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.cyberpolice.ir/news/147107/24-%D8%B4%D8%A7%DB%8C%D8%B9%D9%87-%D9%BE%D8%B1%D8%A7%DA%A9%D9%86-%D9%81%D8%B6%D8%A7%DB%8C-%D9%85%D8%AC%D8%A7%D8%B2%DB%8C-%D8%AF%D8%B1-%D8%AE%D8%B5%D9%88%D8%B5-%D8%A8%DB%8C%D9%85%D8%A7%D8%B1%DB%8C-%DA%A9%D8%B1%D9%88%D9%86%D8%A7-%D9%88%DB%8C%D8%B1%D9%88%D8%B3-%D8%AF%D8%B3%D8%AA%DA%AF%DB%8C%D8%B1-%D8%B4%D8%AF%D9%86%D8%AF-%C2%A0"&gt;
   24 individuals have so far been arrested for spreading rumours
  &lt;/a&gt;
  about the virus, with 118 receiving a warning.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  'Totally fabricated'
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Misleading posts linked to senior officials have gone viral on Iranian social media in recent days.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://twitter.com/vahabzadeh_ali/status/1231871424618430465"&gt;
   A fake letter attributed to Health Minister Saeed Namaki
  &lt;/a&gt;
  claimed he had tendered his resignation to President Hassan Rouhani due to the ministry's "inability to manage" the outbreak.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Mr Namaki said in a statement that
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://bit.ly/2Vu8ELC"&gt;
   the letter was "false"
  &lt;/a&gt;
  .
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  An examination of the letter using an image verification tool also shows basic manipulation techniques were used to create it.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51673053"&gt;
    Coronavirus kills 210 in Iran - hospital sources
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51628484"&gt;
    Iran's deputy health minister tests positive for coronavirus
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51642926"&gt;
    How is Iran responding to the outbreak?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51651454"&gt;
    Iran 'has no plans to quarantine virus-hit cities'
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  An audio clip attributed to deputy health minister and head of Iran's taskforce on Covid-19, Iraj Harirchi, was shared on the Telegram messaging app.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Mr Harirchi had previously declared that "quarantines belong to the Stone Age", before admitting that
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51628484"&gt;
   he had tested positive for the disease
  &lt;/a&gt;
  .
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-with-caption"&gt;
  &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder"&gt;
   &lt;img class="media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image narrative-video-placeholder" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p084sfrq.jpg" /&gt;
   &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder__caption"&gt;
    Media playback is unsupported on your device
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder"&gt;
    &lt;div class="media-player-wrapper"&gt;
     &lt;figure class="js-media-player-unprocessed media-player"&gt;
     &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-with-caption__caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Media caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   Deputy Health Minister Iraj Harirchi mopped his brow at a news conference before testing positive for coronavirus disease
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In the audio clip,
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://twitter.com/timsar_nader/status/1232991175340105728"&gt;
   a man who sounds like Mr Harirchi claims there are more than 10,000 confirmed cases
  &lt;/a&gt;
  and 1,400 deaths in the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But the clip is actually a voice impression, and is different from Mr Harirchi's local accent.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A ministry official tweeted to say
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://twitter.com/vahabzadeh_ali/status/1232956571937902594"&gt;
   the clip was "totally fabricated"
  &lt;/a&gt;
  .
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Masoumeh Ebtekar, vice-president for women and family affairs, is another high-ranking official
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-51665631"&gt;
   who tested positive for the virus
  &lt;/a&gt;
  .
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  An
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://twitter.com/marhoomakbar/status/1233256694614036480"&gt;
   image of Ms Ebtekar in a hospital bed
  &lt;/a&gt;
  was shared on Twitter, with criticism that none of the visitors wore masks or kept their distance from her.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But a reverse search shows
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://bit.ly/3apGYMj"&gt;
   the photo was taken in 2014
  &lt;/a&gt;
  , after Ms Ebtekar sustained injuries in a car accident.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  'Kill the virus'
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  From the outset of the coronavirus outbreak in Iran, false advice on prevention and treatment has been shared on digital platforms.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The Isna agency spoke with a "Persian medicine expert" at the health ministry who suggested
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://bit.ly/2PzpuEY"&gt;
   "gargling vinegar and rosewater or vinegar and salt"
  &lt;/a&gt;
  would protect against the Covid-19.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://twitter.com/khabaronlinee/status/1231466311022206982"&gt;
   The Khabar Online news website tweeted
  &lt;/a&gt;
  that drinks containing mint or white willow, and spices like saffron, turmeric, and cinnamon would strengthen the lungs and the immune system against the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A fabricated post attributed to Iranian-German neurosurgeon and medical scientist Majid Samii
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://twitter.com/digishahrvand/status/1227599766135152640"&gt;
   claimed consuming dates, honey or garlic would "kill the virus"
  &lt;/a&gt;
  .
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  And actress Behnoush Bakhtiari faced criticism for an Instagram video in which she suggested to her 8.1 million followers that a product
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/B8_05vqHir5/"&gt;
   "made from herbs based on traditional medicine"
  &lt;/a&gt;
  would help with the prevention of a number of viral diseases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Following a wave of criticism, she said she had not claimed the product would cure the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  None of these suggestions can be seen in the
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public"&gt;
   World Health Organization's official advice for the public
  &lt;/a&gt;
  on protective measures against the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  'Hybrid warfare'
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Conspiracy theories have also found their way onto social media.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Ali Akbar Raefipour, a public speaker and conspiracy theorist with a huge following among young hardliners,
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://twitter.com/a_raefipour1/status/1233007474812293121"&gt;
   claimed that the virus was part of a "hybrid warfare" programme
  &lt;/a&gt;
  waged by the US on China and Iran.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    AFP/GETTY IMAGES
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  He had also suggested the virus might be an example of
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://twitter.com/a_raefipour1/status/1232413013866635264"&gt;
   "biological warfare"
  &lt;/a&gt;
  .
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Baseless
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/blogs-trending-51271037"&gt;
   suggestions that the Covid-19 might be a "bioweapon" or "planned"
  &lt;/a&gt;
  had previously appeared on the internet.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The virus is believed to have emerged from illegally traded wildlife at a seafood market in the Chinese city of Wuhan.
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 06:07:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coronavirus: Rescuing China's animals during the outbreak</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-51614957</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="Dogs on a street in Shenzhen" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/3670/production/_111063931_i.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Supplied
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    Animal rescue groups say they are seeing an increasing number of animals abandoned across the country
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  Volunteers in China say they're struggling to keep up with the number of animals being abandoned as the country battles the virus outbreak.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  More than 2,000 people in China have died and more than 78,000 infections have been reported in the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Pet owners who fall sick or are caught up in quarantine can't take their animals with them, and despite reassurance from the World Health Organization that animals can't carry the virus, others are being dumped.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "I have rescued lots of dogs this month, most have been abandoned by their owners," one volunteer from Furry Angels Heaven in Wuhan, the centre of the outbreak, told the BBC.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "One animal's owner has coronavirus and was sent to quarantine. Fortunately a policeman sent her to me."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The volunteer didn't want to reveal her name because of fears of official repercussions. She said she has 35 dogs and 28 cats in her apartment in addition to the animal rescue centre she helps operate.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Furry Angels Heaven
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    Dogs found abandoned in a box in Wuhan by rescuers from Furry Angels Heaven
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "It's a bad situation here. We are not allowed to go outside and I am afraid my dogs and cats will be out of food soon. I am worried if I or my family get infected with the virus then all of the dogs and cats could be killed by policemen."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Without income from its regular paid work at the moment, she fears the animal centre's savings could be used up soon.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "It's expensive to rescue these animals", she said.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As soon as the lockdown is over, the animals will be available for adoption.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/technology-51646309"&gt;
    Coronavirus: Fake news is spreading fast
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/business-51639487"&gt;
    Coronavirus: Chinese workers offered free transport
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The coronavirus outbreak began in late December, but it worsened as people went away for Chinese New Year in January. Many people went to visit family in other cities, leaving food behind for their pets thinking they would only be away for a few days.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But then the lockdown was introduced. More than 60 million people in Hubei province were placed under travel restrictions. People were unable to return to their homes and the food they had left for their pets had started to run out.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Furry Angels Heaven
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    One volunteer has 35 dogs and 28 cats inside her apartment
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Panicked pet owners used social media site Weibo to plead for help.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "Help! I live in Ezhou City and my cat is trapped," wrote one woman from a town near Wuhan.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "I'm asking a caring person nearby to help me feed the cat. I am willing to pay for it, thank the caring person and everyone else, please share."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    The empty streets of Wuhan during the lockdown
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  One volunteer, who gave his name as Lao Mao, is part of a group that provides assistance to people who cannot access their animals. So far his group has helped to rescue more than 1,000 pets.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Video footage posted on social media accounts show Lao Mao's team entering properties, feeding animals and providing them with medical care.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "There are more animals needing help these days," he told the BBC.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  He said that the situation now for animals is "very dangerous".
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "So many of them have starved to death, only a few of them can reach me for help. There's nothing much I can do but I will save as many as I can."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-asia-china-51176409"&gt;
    How could coronavirus harm asthmatics, and other questions
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-asia-china-51628693"&gt;
    How China is keeping busy during quarantine
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It's not just animal rescuers in Wuhan that are feeling the strain. Animal groups across China told the BBC that they were struggling to deal with the current situation and strict quarantine measures.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Animal Rescue Shanghai told the BBC that the situation is a "nightmare".
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "It is high season during Chinese New Year which means a lot of dogs are kicked out and due to coronavirus, a lot of flights have been cancelled. We now have over 350 dogs for a place sized for 120," said, Nana, who works at the shelter. We are really desperate."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  An experienced rescuer in Shenzhen who did not want to give her name also said Chinese New Year was a busy time of year for animal abandonments, but that she has never encountered one every single day.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    SUPPLIED
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    One rescuer said because of the lockdown, businesses are not feeding stray animals
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "Businesses are closed so there is no-one to feed the strays. It started being very common to see roaming cats and dogs and hear them fighting and barking and meowing much more than usual."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  She said at one point, she saw a partially eaten mother dog with her puppies still around her.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But she said that as the situation has intensified, volunteers have joined forces like never before to handle the amount of animals in need.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "Community support has been really heart-warming, many people help, volunteer, support and share or decide to adopt or foster.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "Both Chinese people and foreigners have united to help each other help animals."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-with-caption"&gt;
  &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder"&gt;
   &lt;img class="media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image narrative-video-placeholder" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p084nz3m.jpg" /&gt;
   &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder__caption"&gt;
    Media playback is unsupported on your device
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder"&gt;
    &lt;div class="media-player-wrapper"&gt;
     &lt;figure class="js-media-player-unprocessed media-player"&gt;
     &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-with-caption__caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Media caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   'I'm not leaving China without my dog'
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 02:40:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coronavirus: What are the chances of dying?</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51674743</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="Two medical workers put on protective clothing at a hospital to treat coronavirus patients in Wuhan, China." class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/4873/production/_111074581_gettyimages-1203459555.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    More than 50 countries have now confirmed cases
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  Researchers currently think that between five and 40 coronavirus cases in 1,000 will result in death, with a best guess of nine in 1,000 or about 1%.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But it depends on a range of factors: your age, sex and general health and the health system you are in.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  How hard is it to work out the death rate?
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It is PhD-level hard. Even counting cases is tricky.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Most cases of most viruses will go uncounted because people tend not to visit the doctor with mild symptoms.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The different death rates we are seeing reported around the world are unlikely to be due to different versions of the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/media/imperial-college/medicine/sph/ide/gida-fellowships/Imperial-College-2019-nCoV-severity-10-02-2020.pdf"&gt;
   According to research by Imperial College
  &lt;/a&gt;
  , it's because different countries are better or worse at spotting the milder, harder to count cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  So under-reporting cases makes it easy to overestimate the death rate. But you can also get it wrong in the other direction.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It takes time before an infection results in recovery or death.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  If you include all cases that haven't yet had a chance to run their course, you will underestimate the death rate because you are missing the cases that will end in death later.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51048366"&gt;
    Coronavirus: All you need to know
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-51235105"&gt;
    A visual guide to the outbreak
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Scientists combine individual pieces of evidence about each of these questions to build a picture of the death rate.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  For example, they estimate the proportion of cases with mild symptoms from small, defined groups of people who are monitored very tightly, like people on repatriated flights.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But slightly different answers from those pieces of evidence will add up to big changes in the overall picture.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  If you just use data from Hubei, where the death rate has been much higher than elsewhere in China, then the overall death rate will look much worse.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  So scientists give a range as well as a best current estimate.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But even that doesn't tell the full story because there is no single death rate.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/explainers-51632801"&gt;
    How is the UK getting ready for coronavirus?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  What's the risk for people like me?
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Some types of people are more likely to die if they contract coronavirus: the elderly, the unwell and, maybe, men.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In the first big
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-51540981"&gt;
   analysis of more than 44,000 cases from China
  &lt;/a&gt;
  , the death rate was ten times higher in the very elderly compared to the middle-aged.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The death rates were lowest for the under 30s - there were eight deaths in 4,500 cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  And deaths were at least five times more common among people with diabetes, high blood pressure or heart or breathing problems.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  There was even a slightly higher number of deaths among men compared to women.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  All of these factors interact with each other and we don't yet have a complete picture of the risk for every type of person in every location.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    At least 621 people were infected on the Diamond Princess cruise ship in Japan
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  What's the risk for people where I live?
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A group of 80-year-old men in China could have very different risks to men of the same age in Europe or Africa.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Your prognosis also depends on the treatment you get.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In turn, that depends on what is available and the stage of the epidemic.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  If the epidemic takes off, then healthcare systems could get swamped with cases - there are only so many intensive care units or ventilators available in any given area.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    Coronavirus patients in England are being treated at a specialist centre at the Royal Free Hospital in London
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  Is it more dangerous than flu?
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  We can't compare mortality rates because many people with mild flu symptoms choose never to visit a doctor.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  So we don't know how many cases there are of flu, or any new virus every year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But flu continues to kill people in the UK, as it does every winter.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As the data evolves, scientists will develop a clearer picture of who would be most at risk should a coronavirus outbreak arrive in the UK.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The basic advice from the WHO is that you can protect yourself from all respiratory viruses by washing your hands, avoiding people who are coughing and sneezing and trying not to touch your eyes, nose and mouth.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;hr class="story-body__line" /&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   Have you been affected by the coronavirus? Or do you have any information to share? Get in touch by emailing
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-email" href="mailto:haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk?subject=Coronavirus51673068"&gt;
   &lt;span class="icon email"&gt;
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-body__link-email-text"&gt;
    haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   .
  &lt;/strong&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Please include a contact number if you are willing to speak to a BBC journalist. You can also contact us in the following ways:
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   WhatsApp:
   &lt;strong&gt;
    +44 7756 165803
   &lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   Tweet:
   &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="http://twitter.com/BBC_HaveYourSay"&gt;
    @BBC_HaveYourSay
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   Send pictures/video to
   &lt;a class="story-body__link-email" href="mailto:yourpics@bbc.co.uk"&gt;
    &lt;span class="icon email"&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="story-body__link-email-text"&gt;
     yourpics@bbc.co.uk
    &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/send/u16904890"&gt;
    Upload your pictures / video here
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   Please read our
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/usingthebbc/terms/"&gt;
    terms &amp;amp; conditions
   &lt;/a&gt;
   and
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/usingthebbc/privacy-policy/"&gt;
    privacy policy
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  ,
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:40:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coronavirus: Global shares suffer worst week since financial crisis</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51639654</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="NYSE traders" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/1EF7/production/_111072970_nyse_reuters.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Reuters
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    The Dow Jones recorded its biggest ever points fall on Thursday
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  US markets have suffered their worst week since the global financial crisis of 2008, as fears over the impact of the coronavirus continued to grip investors.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The three main US indexes ended the week down 10% or more from last Friday, despite a last-minute rally in prices.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Earlier, the main European markets fell sharply, with London's FTSE 100 index down 3.2% for the day.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Investors are worried the coronavirus could spark a global recession.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The Dow settled 1.4% lower on Friday, recovering from earlier lows, while the S&amp;amp;P sank 0.8% and the Nasdaq was roughly flat.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Amid the sell-off, Federal Reserve chair Jerome Powell put out an unusual statement, saying the US central bank was "closely monitoring" developments.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "The fundamentals of the US economy remain strong. However, the coronavirus poses evolving risks to economic activity," he said. "We will use our tools and act as appropriate to support the economy."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The news of more coronavirus cases, notably in Italy, has raised concerns of a much larger economic effect than previously expected.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Bank of England Governor Mark Carney on Friday warned the outbreak could lead to a downgrade of the UK's growth prospects.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Other countries are also reassessing their economic forecasts, as hundreds of firms warn of disruptions to their supply chains and a decline in consumer demand.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;!-- ONE DAY CHART --&gt;
 
 
 &lt;div class="constraint"&gt;
  &lt;div class="box sixteen-nine"&gt;
   &lt;div class="news-vj-spw-wrapper" id="xnqqweem-core-content"&gt;
    
    
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 
 
 &lt;p&gt;
  US tech giants
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51539322"&gt;
   Apple
  &lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51654691"&gt;
   Microsoft
  &lt;/a&gt;
  are among the companies that have said their business will be affected, while investment bank Goldman Sachs warned on Thursday that the coronavirus is likely to wipe out any growth in US company profits this year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Shares in airlines have been especially hard-hit as travel bans are imposed and companies limit staff travel. On Friday, airline group IAG - which owns British Airways and Iberia - said its earnings had been affected by "weaker demand" as a result of the outbreak.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  More anxiety ahead
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "A known unknown" is how one major company boss described the economic fallout of coronavirus to the BBC.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But what the markets have woken up to - perhaps belatedly - is that the disruption to the economic activity from coronavirus is wider, deeper and perhaps longer lasting than previously assumed.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As major outbreaks spring up outside China, it is clear that it is not just global supply chains but also demand from consumers that's suffering, as efforts to contain the virus keep them away from shops, bars and restaurants.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  What is unknown is exactly how bad and how lasting the impact could be. But what is known is that this comes at an already tricky time for the global economy with Japan, Italy, China and the UK among those already seeing growth faltering.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As economists slash their growth forecasts, policymakers are debating how much they can do to help, given how low interest rates remain. What's entirely clear is that investors face more anxiety ahead.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Mayank Mishra, a strategist at Standard Chartered Bank, said: "Previously the market had taken some comfort in the falling infection rates in China as a result of containment measures put in place earlier.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "But the spread of the coronavirus infection outside China, with clusters emerging in South Korea, Italy and Japan, has increased concerns significantly."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51671193"&gt;
    BA owner and EasyJet hit by coronavirus
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/business-51658361"&gt;
    Dettol sales surge amid coronavirus fears
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-51665631"&gt;
    Coronavirus outbreak at ‘decisive point’
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In Europe, Germany's Dax index fell 4.2%, while France's Cac 40 index sank 3.9%.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Earlier on Friday, in Asia, Japan's Nikkei 225 index dropped 3.7%, bringing its fall for the week to more than 9%. China's Shanghai Composite index also fell 3.7% on Friday.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Traders fled to less risky investments, such as government debt, sending bond yields to new lows. Meanwhile, oil prices also fell on fears the virus would hurt demand, with Brent prices dropping more than 3% to about $50 a barrel on Friday, the lowest level for more than a year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  US President Donald Trump, who has claimed credit for a sharp rise in share prices during his tenure, blamed the falls on investor fear of "the unknown" - as well as concerns about the Democratic candidates hoping to challenge him in November's presidential election.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "People look at it and they say how long will this last," he said. "It's an election ... I don't think that's helping."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Several key global market indexes - including the FTSE 100 and the Dow Jones - have fallen more than 10% from recent highs. A drop of that magnitude is generally referred to as a correction.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  However, share prices were hovering at record levels before the sell-off started, noted Sonja Laud, chief investment officer at Legal &amp;amp; General Investment Management.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The Dow and S&amp;amp;P 500 have now retreated roughly to where they were in August, while the Nasdaq has returned to December prices.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "What markets are trying to digest is how long this is going to go on and what the economic damage will be," she said.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;!-- ONE DAY CHART --&gt;
 
 
 &lt;div class="constraint"&gt;
  &lt;div class="box sixteen-nine"&gt;
   &lt;div class="news-vj-spw-wrapper" id="zwylwock-core-content"&gt;
    
    
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 
 
 &lt;p&gt;
  Many analysts now predict the US central bank will cut interest rates in an attempt to counter any impact. James Bullard, who sits on the Fed's board of governors, said Friday that cuts are "a possibility" should the virus continue to spread, but he warned that market expectations would not force the bank to act.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Ms Laud said that many central banks had little room for manoeuvre, because rates are already so low.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "Realistically it's mostly the Fed and to some extent the Bank of England that still have the chance to cut rates," she told the BBC.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "I think there will be a huge focus on governments to step up fiscal stimulus under the assumption there is not a lot more that central banks can do to stimulate the economy."
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 22:05:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coronavirus: Shares face worst week since financial crisis</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51639654</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="NYSE traders" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/1EF7/production/_111072970_nyse_reuters.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Reuters
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    The Dow Jones recorded its biggest ever points fall on Thursday
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  US shares have sunk further as stock markets face their worst week since the global financial crisis of 2008.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The Dow Jones, hit by its biggest ever daily points drop on Thursday, fell  more than 2% as fears over the impact of the coronavirus continued to grip investors.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The main European markets also fell sharply on Friday, with London's FTSE 100 index down 3.4%.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Investors are worried the coronavirus impact could spark a global recession.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The news of more coronavirus cases, notably in Italy, has raised concerns of a much larger economic effect than previously expected.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  On Friday, Bank of England Governor Mark Carney said the outbreak could lead to a downgrade of the UK's growth prospects.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Other countries are also reassessing their economic forecasts, as dozens of firms warn of disruptions to their supply chains and a decline in consumer demand.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;!-- ONE DAY CHART --&gt;
 
 
 &lt;div class="constraint"&gt;
  &lt;div class="box sixteen-nine"&gt;
   &lt;div class="news-vj-spw-wrapper" id="ghsifokg-core-content"&gt;
    
    
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 
 
 &lt;p&gt;
  US tech giants
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51539322"&gt;
   Apple
  &lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51654691"&gt;
   Microsoft
  &lt;/a&gt;
  are among the companies that have said their business will be affected, while investment bank Goldman Sachs warned on Thursday that the coronavirus is likely to wipe out any growth in US company profits this year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Shares in airlines have been especially hard-hit as travel bans are imposed and companies limit staff travel. On Friday, airline group IAG - which owns British Airways and Iberia - said its earnings had been affected by "weaker demand" as a result of the outbreak.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As the sell-off continued on Friday, the head of the US central bank, Jerome Powell, put out an unusual statement, saying Federal Reserve was "closely monitoring" developments.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "The fundamentals of the US economy remain strong. However, the coronavirus poses evolving risks to economic activity," he said. "We will use our tools and act as appropriate to support the economy."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  More anxiety ahead
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "A known unknown" is how one major company boss described the economic fallout of coronavirus to the BBC.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But what the markets have woken up to - perhaps belatedly - is that the disruption to the economic activity from coronavirus is wider, deeper and perhaps longer lasting than previously assumed.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As major outbreaks spring up outside China, it is clear that it is not just global supply chains but also demand from consumers that's suffering, as efforts to contain the virus keep them away from shops, bars and restaurants.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  What is unknown is exactly how bad and how lasting the impact could be. But what is known is that this comes at an already tricky time for the global economy with Japan, Italy, China and the UK among those already seeing growth faltering.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As economists slash their growth forecasts, policymakers are debating how much they can do to help, given how low interest rates remain. What's entirely clear is that investors face more anxiety ahead.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Mayank Mishra, a strategist at Standard Chartered Bank, said: "Previously the market had taken some comfort in the falling infection rates in China as a result of containment measures put in place earlier.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "But the spread of the coronavirus infection outside China, with clusters emerging in South Korea, Italy and Japan, has increased concerns significantly."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51671193"&gt;
    BA owner and EasyJet hit by coronavirus
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/business-51658361"&gt;
    Dettol sales surge amid coronavirus fears
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-51665631"&gt;
    Coronavirus outbreak at ‘decisive point’
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The S&amp;amp;P 500 fell about 2% on Friday, while the Nasdaq was about 1% lower.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The worries also hit the main European share indexes, sending Germany's Dax index down 4.2% and France's Cac 40 index down 3.9%.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Earlier in Asia, Japan's Nikkei 225 index dropped 3.7%, bringing its fall for the week to more than 9%. China's Shanghai Composite index also fell 3.7% on Friday.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The price of Brent crude oil also fell on fears the virus would hurt demand, dropping nearly 2% to $51.21 a barrel on Friday, its lowest level for more than a year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In the US, White House economic advisor Larry Kudlow sought to calm market fears, telling reporters that he did not think the market plunge was a broader warning about the economy.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "I just don't think this short-term stock market plunge is going to have any long-term effects," he said. "Sometimes the psychology is a lot worse than the fact."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Several key global market indexes - including the FTSE 100 and the Dow Jones - have fallen more than 10% from recent highs. A drop of that magnitude is generally referred to as a correction.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  However, share prices were hovering at record levels before the sell-off started, noted Sonja Laud, chief investment officer at Legal &amp;amp; General Investment Management.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "What markets are trying to digest is how long this is going to go on and what the economic damage will be," she said.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;!-- ONE DAY CHART --&gt;
 
 
 &lt;div class="constraint"&gt;
  &lt;div class="box sixteen-nine"&gt;
   &lt;div class="news-vj-spw-wrapper" id="retzlyoy-core-content"&gt;
    
    
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 
 
 &lt;p&gt;
  Many analysts now predict the US central bank will cut interest rates in an attempt to counter any impact. James Bullard, who sits on the Fed's board of governors, said Friday that cuts are "a possibility" should the virus continue to spread, but he warned that market expectations would not force the bank to act.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Ms Laud said that many central banks had little room for manoeuvre, because rates are already so low.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "Realistically it's mostly the Fed and to some extent the Bank of England that still have the chance to cut rates," she told the BBC.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "I think there will be a huge focus on governments to step up fiscal stimulus under the assumption there is not a lot more that central banks can do to stimulate the economy."
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 19:59:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A visual guide to this outbreak</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-51235105</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="Man with a face mask in Hong Kong" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/03F9/production/_111071010_mask_man_getty_976.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  A fast-moving virus originating in China and known as the "new coronavirus" has infected tens of thousands of Chinese citizens and spread to more than 50 countries. It has claimed nearly 3,000 lives so far.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Here are 11 maps and charts that will help you understand what is going on.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  1. New infections outside China top those within
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Almost 80,000 people in China have been infected with the coronavirus - known officially as
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/q-a-coronaviruses"&gt;
   Covid-19
  &lt;/a&gt;
  - since the virus's discovery in the city of Wuhan, Hubei province, in December.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Although the vast majority of cases of the respiratory infection, which causes pneumonia-like symptoms, remain in China, the virus is now spreading faster outside the country than inside.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Coronavirus has infected more than 4,500 people across the globe, according to World Health Organization (WHO) figures.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  However, infectious disease specialists at Imperial College London estimate about two thirds of COVID-19 cases originating in mainland China
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/mrc-global-infectious-disease-analysis/news--wuhan-coronavirus/"&gt;
   remain undetected worldwide.
  &lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  This could mean "multiple chains of as yet undetected human-to-human transmission" internationally, they say.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The three biggest international outbreaks detected so far have been in South Korea, with more than 2,300 cases, on board the British-registered Diamond Princess cruise ship docked in Yokohama, Japan, which has seen more than 700 people infected, and Italy, with more than 640 confirmed cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In a sign the disease is spreading further afield, Brazil announced Latin America's first case on Thursday and the first cases in Africa have been confirmed in Algeria, Egypt and Nigeria. New Zealand has also confirmed its first case.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Within Europe, Austria, Croatia, Greece, Norway, Switzerland, Georgia and North Macedonia have reported their first cases, while more infections have been announced in Spain, France and Germany.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  On the Spanish island of Tenerife, up to 1,000 guests have been locked down in a hotel after an Italian doctor and his wife tested positive.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Governments across Europe are stepping up preparations, as more cases are detected.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  French President Emmanuel Macron has warned that a coronavirus epidemic in France is inevitable.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51048366"&gt;
    What are the symptoms?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51048366"&gt;
    How worried should we be?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  2. The virus has pandemic potential
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The jump in the number of daily confirmed cases internationally has raised fears the outbreak could become a pandemic - when an infectious disease spreads easily from person to person in many parts of the world.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The spread has reached a "decisive point" and has "pandemic potential", WHO head Dr Tedros Ghebreyesus says.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Dr Tedros urged governments to act swiftly to contain the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "This is not a time for fear," he said. "This is a time for taking action to prevent infection and save lives now."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Countries around the world are continuing to ramp up measures to battle the disease's spread.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Many have advised their citizens to avoid all non-essential travel to China and other affected countries, while others have announced screening measures for passengers arriving from places with outbreaks.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Stock markets around the world have
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51664652"&gt;
   fallen sharply
  &lt;/a&gt;
  amid fears that such increased travel restrictions will prevent business activity.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A number of international conferences and sporting events have also been cancelled, including Six Nations rugby matches with Italy in Dublin that were to be held on 7 and 8 March.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The US has declared the outbreak a public health emergency, the UK has deemed it a
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-51442314"&gt;
   "serious and imminent threat" to public health
  &lt;/a&gt;
  and Japan has closed all its schools.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The WHO declared the crisis a global health emergency on 30 January.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The organisation has confirmed it will not formally "declare" a pandemic for the new coronavirus, though the term may still be used "colloquially".
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51628753"&gt;
    How close are we to a pandemic?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  3. South Korea, Italy and Iran are among the worst-affected countries
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  South Korea, Italy and Iran have all seen significant outbreaks of cases in recent days, with South Korea the worst-affected country after China.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   South Korea
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  's biggest virus clusters have been linked to a religious group near the south-eastern city of Daegu, which has a population of around 2.5m.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Meanwhile in
  &lt;strong&gt;
   Italy
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  , the country's authorities have announced a series of measures to try to halt the virus's spread. It is not yet clear how it entered the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Eleven towns in northern Italy at the centre of the outbreak - home to a total of 55,000 people - have been quarantined. Schools, universities and cinemas have been closed and several public events cancelled.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The UK has advised against travelling to the region.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Several countries including Algeria, Denmark, Romania and Spain have reported infections linked to Italy.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   Iran
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  confirmed it has seen a number of cases of the virus, most of them in the holy city of Qom, south of Tehran.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Iranian officials have asked people not to go to Qom, but have not shut a shrine in the city that attracts millions of Shia pilgrims each year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The government also said it had no plans to quarantine any cities and towns. despite fears of a regional epidemic.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;
   Note: Map based on Iran's Ministry of Health figures, given on state TV, which may differ from WHO numbers
  &lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Iran has been the source of dozens of cases in neighbouring countries, including Afghanistan, Bahrain, Iraq, Kuwait, Oman and Pakistan.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In response, many of Iran's neighbours have announced the temporary closure of their borders with the country.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Saudi Arabia has also
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51658061"&gt;
   temporarily banned pilgrims from entering the country
  &lt;/a&gt;
  to visit the holy sites of Mecca and Medina and suspended visas for tourists from countries with confirmed cases of the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-51645902"&gt;
    Coronavirus cases surge to 400 in Italy
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-51658061"&gt;
    Saudi Arabia suspends entry for pilgrims
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  4. China still has by far the most cases
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The number of overall coronavirus cases in China has been rising since January.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The country accounts for almost 79,000 of the global 83,000 cases - and thousands more Chinese citizens are under medical observation.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Government and regional officials have introduced a number of tight restrictions in a bid to reduce infections, including cancelling flights, closing schools and workplaces and ordering some cities to go into lockdown.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Authorities also postponed the country's annual parliamentary gathering - the National People's Congress.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Hubei province - the centre of the outbreak - remains the worst affected, seeing by far the biggest number of cases of the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-portrait no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Its capital city of Wuhan, home to 11 million people, has been under lockdown since 23 January, with transport links into and out of the city closed.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The origins of the new coronavirus have been linked to illegally traded wildlife at Wuhan's seafood market, which sells live animals including bats, rabbits and marmots. However, the exact source of the outbreak has not been identified.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Hundreds of foreign nationals have been evacuated from Wuhan by several governments including the US, France and Britain.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-51628693"&gt;
    How China is keeping busy during quarantine
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  5. Daily infections and deaths in China have been comparatively low recently
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  New cases announced in China have remained low over recent days, compared with numbers seen in early-mid February, according to official figures.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Figures have stayed in the hundreds rather than the thousands for the last week, following a spike in mid-February.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Officials in Hubei province have come under fire for their handling of the virus outbreak, including causing confusion by changing the criteria used to count the number of cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Changes to the way patients were diagnosed half way through February caused a brief spike in the number of confirmed cases, but this change was later reversed, causing a later dip.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The number of deaths announced each day by the Chinese authorities have been dropping for most of the last few days. Like the daily confirmed cases, daily death figures saw a spike caused by the change in diagnosis criteria in mid-February.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Wuhan continues to account for the majority of new cases and deaths in China.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Despite the drop in deaths, the new coronavirus has overtaken the 2003 Sars epidemic in both confirmed cases and deaths.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The Sars - severe acute respiratory syndrome - outbreak lasted around eight months and killed 774 people out of around 8,100 confirmed cases.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A study of 44,000 coronavirus cases by the Chinese Centre for Disease Control and Prevention found that more than 80% had been mild, with the sick and elderly most at risk, while 4.7% had been critical.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A report on the early stages of the outbreak by the Lancet medical journal said most patients who died from the virus had had pre-existing conditions.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Medical researchers and scientists say it is too early to accurately predict how the virus will spread or calculate the death rate, partly due to mild cases remaining untested and unrecorded and a time lag of reporting infections.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As there is not yet a specific anti-viral treatment for coronavirus, people with the infection are currently being treated for their symptoms.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;
   By Lucy Rodgers, Mike Hills, Dominic Bailey and Wesley Stephenson
  &lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 18:43:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coronavirus: Shares face worst week since financial crisis</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51639654</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="NYSE traders" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/1EF7/production/_111072970_nyse_reuters.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Reuters
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    The Dow Jones recorded its biggest ever points fall on Thursday
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  US shares have sunk further as stock markets suffer their worst week since the global financial crisis of 2008.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The Dow Jones, hit by its biggest ever daily points drop on Thursday, was down about 2% in mid-day trade as fears over the impact of the coronavirus continued to grip investors.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The main European markets also fell sharply on Friday, with London's FTSE 100 index down 3.4%.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Investors are worried the coronavirus impact could spark a global recession.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The news of more coronavirus cases, notably in Italy, has raised concerns of a much larger economic effect than previously expected.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://news.sky.com/story/coronavirus-could-mean-economic-growth-downgrade-for-uk-mark-carney-warns-11944874"&gt;
   In an interview with Sky News
  &lt;/a&gt;
  , Bank of England governor Mark Carney warned that the coronavirus outbreak could lead to a downgrade of the UK's economic growth prospects.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;!-- ONE DAY CHART --&gt;
 
 
 &lt;div class="constraint"&gt;
  &lt;div class="box sixteen-nine"&gt;
   &lt;div class="news-vj-spw-wrapper" id="rezyiehr-core-content"&gt;
    
    
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 
 
 &lt;p&gt;
  Other countries are also reassessing their economic forecasts, as dozens of firms warn of disruptions to their supply chains and a decline in consumer demand.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  US tech giants
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51539322"&gt;
   Apple
  &lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51654691"&gt;
   Microsoft
  &lt;/a&gt;
  are among the firms that have said their business will be affected, while US investment bank Goldman Sachs warned on Thursday that the coronavirus is likely to wipe out any growth in US company profits this year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Shares in airlines have been especially hard-hit as travel bans are imposed and companies limit staff travel. On Friday, airline group IAG - which owns British Airways and Iberia - said its earnings had been affected by "weaker demand" as a result of the outbreak.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;!-- ONE DAY CHART --&gt;
 
 
 &lt;div class="constraint"&gt;
  &lt;div class="box sixteen-nine"&gt;
   &lt;div class="news-vj-spw-wrapper" id="bdtwvedr-core-content"&gt;
    
    
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 
 
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  More anxiety ahead
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "A known unknown" is how one major company boss described the economic fallout of coronavirus to the BBC.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But what the markets have woken up to - perhaps belatedly - is that the disruption to the economic activity from coronavirus is wider, deeper and perhaps longer lasting than previously assumed.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As major outbreaks spring up outside China, it is clear that it is not just global supply chains but also demand from consumers that's suffering, as efforts to contain the virus keep them away from shops, bars and restaurants.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  What is unknown is exactly how bad and how lasting the impact could be. But what is known is that this comes at an already tricky time for the global economy with Japan, Italy, China and the UK among those already seeing growth faltering.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As economists slash their growth forecasts, policymakers are debating how much they can do to help, given how low interest rates remain. What's entirely clear is that investors face more anxiety ahead.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Mayank Mishra, a strategist at Standard Chartered Bank, said: "Previously the market had taken some comfort in the falling infection rates in China as a result of containment measures put in place earlier.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "But the spread of the coronavirus infection outside China, with clusters emerging in South Korea, Italy and Japan, has increased concerns significantly."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51671193"&gt;
    BA owner and EasyJet hit by coronavirus
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/business-51658361"&gt;
    Dettol sales surge amid coronavirus fears
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-51665631"&gt;
    Coronavirus outbreak at ‘decisive point’
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The S&amp;amp;P 500 fell about 1.2% on Friday, while the Nasdaq was about 0.5% lower.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The worries also hit the main European share indexes, sending Germany's Dax index down 4.2% and France's Cac 40 index down 3.9%.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Earlier in Asia, Japan's Nikkei 225 index dropped 3.7%, bringing its fall for the week to more than 9%. China's Shanghai Composite index also fell 3.7% on Friday.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The price of Brent crude oil also fell on fears the virus would hurt demand, dropping nearly 2% to $51.21 a barrel on Friday, its lowest level for more than a year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In the US, White House economic advisor Larry Kudlow sought to calm market fears, telling reporters that he did not think the market plunge was a broader warning about the economy.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "I just don't think this short-term stock market plunge is going to have any long-term effects," he said. "Sometimes the psychology is a lot worse than the fact."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Several key global market indexes - including the FTSE 100 and the Dow Jones - have fallen more than 10% from recent highs. A drop of that magnitude is generally referred to as a correction.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  However, share prices were hovering at record levels before the sell-off started, noted Sonja Laud, chief investment officer at Legal &amp;amp; General Investment Management.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "What markets are trying to digest is how long this is going to go on and what the economic damage will be," she said.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Many analysts now predict the US central bank will cut interest rates in an attempt to counter any impact. James Bullard, who sits on the Fed's board of governors, said Friday that cuts are "a possibility" should the virus continue to spread, but he warned that market expectations would not force the bank to act.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Ms Laud said that many central banks had little room for manoeuvre, because rates are already so low.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "Realistically it's mostly the Fed and to some extent the Bank of England that still have the chance to cut rates," she told the BBC.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "I think there will be a huge focus on governments to step up fiscal stimulus under the assumption there is not a lot more that central banks can do to stimulate the economy."
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 18:14:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coronavirus: Shares face worst week since global financial crisis</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51639654</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="NYSE traders" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/1EF7/production/_111072970_nyse_reuters.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Reuters
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    The Dow Jones recorded its biggest ever points fall on Thursday
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  US shares have sunk further as stock markets suffer their worst week since the global financial crisis of 2008.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The Dow Jones, hit by its biggest ever daily points drop on Thursday, fell another 3.7% in morning trade as fears over the impact of the coronavirus continued to grip investors.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The main European markets also fell sharply on Friday, with London's FTSE 100 index down more than 3%.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Investors are worried the coronavirus impact could spark a global recession.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The news of more coronavirus cases, notably in Italy, has raised concerns of a much larger economic effect than previously expected.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://news.sky.com/story/coronavirus-could-mean-economic-growth-downgrade-for-uk-mark-carney-warns-11944874"&gt;
   In an interview with Sky News
  &lt;/a&gt;
  , Bank of England governor Mark Carney warned that the coronavirus outbreak could lead to a downgrade of the UK's economic growth prospects.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;!-- ONE DAY CHART --&gt;
 
 
 &lt;div class="constraint"&gt;
  &lt;div class="box sixteen-nine"&gt;
   &lt;div class="news-vj-spw-wrapper" id="nhuvkdlg-core-content"&gt;
    
    
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 
 
 &lt;p&gt;
  Dozens of firms have warned of disruptions to their supply chains and a decline in consumer demand.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  US tech giants
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51539322"&gt;
   Apple
  &lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51654691"&gt;
   Microsoft
  &lt;/a&gt;
  have both said their business will be affected, while US investment bank Goldman Sachs warned on Thursday that it now thinks the coronavirus will wipe out any growth in US company profits this year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Shares in airlines have been especially hard-hit as travel bans are imposed and companies limit staff travel. On Friday, airline group IAG - which owns British Airways and Iberia - said its earnings had been affected by "weaker demand" as a result of the outbreak.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;!-- ONE DAY CHART --&gt;
 
 
 &lt;div class="constraint"&gt;
  &lt;div class="box sixteen-nine"&gt;
   &lt;div class="news-vj-spw-wrapper" id="qpqymtii-core-content"&gt;
    
    
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 
 
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  More anxiety ahead
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "A known unknown" is how one major company boss described the economic fallout of coronavirus to the BBC.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But what the markets have woken up to - perhaps belatedly - is that the disruption to the economic activity from coronavirus is wider, deeper and perhaps longer lasting than previously assumed.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As major outbreaks spring up outside China, it is clear that it is not just global supply chains but also demand from consumers that's suffering, as efforts to contain the virus keep them away from shops, bars and restaurants.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  What is unknown is exactly how bad and how lasting the impact could be. But what is known is that this comes at an already tricky time for the global economy with Japan, Italy, China and the UK among those already seeing growth faltering.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  As economists slash their growth forecasts, policymakers are debating how much they can do to help, given how low interest rates remain. What's entirely clear is that investors face more anxiety ahead.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The S&amp;amp;P 500 and Nasdaq were more than 3% lower in morning trade in New York.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  All the main European share indexes saw big falls on Friday, with Germany's Dax index down 4.4% and France's Cac 40 index falling 3.9%.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Earlier in Asia, Japan's Nikkei 225 index fell 3.7%, bringing its fall for the week to more than 9%. China's Shanghai Composite index also fell 3.7% on Friday.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Russ Mould, investment director at AJ Bell, said: "This has been one of the worst weeks on the markets in a very long time, leaving investors' portfolios battered and bruised."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51671193"&gt;
    BA owner and EasyJet hit by coronavirus
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/business-51658361"&gt;
    Dettol sales surge amid coronavirus fears
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="/news/world-51665631"&gt;
    Coronavirus outbreak at ‘decisive point’
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Mayank Mishra, a strategist at Standard Chartered Bank, said: "Previously the market had taken some comfort in the falling infection rates in China as a result of containment measures put in place earlier.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "But the spread of the coronavirus infection outside China, with clusters emerging in South Korea, Italy and Japan, has increased concerns significantly."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Several key global market indexes - including the FTSE 100 and the Dow Jones - have fallen 10% from recent highs. A drop of that magnitude is generally referred to as a correction.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "What markets are trying to digest is how long this is going to go on and what the economic damage will be," Sonja Laud, chief investment officer at Legal &amp;amp; General Investment Management, told the BBC.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  However, Ms Laud noted that the falls followed a very strong period for shares. "They [this week's falls] are significant if you look at a very short period of time, but if you put it in the context of the very strong markets in 2019, then the starting point has been all-time highs for quite a number of markets."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Many analysts are now expecting the US central bank to cut interest rates to try to counter any impact. However, Ms Laud said that many central banks had little room for manoeuvre, given that rates are already so low.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "Realistically it's mostly the Fed and to some extent the Bank of England that still have the chance to cut rates," she said.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  "I think there will be a huge focus on governments to step up fiscal stimulus under the assumption there is not a lot more that central banks can do to stimulate the economy."
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The oil price has also fallen sharply on fears that the virus outbreak will lead a big drop in demand, as factories reduce or halt production during the outbreak.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The price of Brent crude fell nearly 2% to $51.21 a barrel on Friday, its lowest level for more than a year.
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 15:13:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sun Yang: Eight-year ban for Chinese Olympic champion</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/swimming/51670931</link><description></description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 14:24:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coronavirus: Can it harm breastfed babies, and other questions</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-51176409</link><description>&lt;div class="story-body__inner"&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width lead"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;img alt="A mother breastfeeding her son" class="js-image-replace" height="549" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/320/cpsprodpb/797D/production/_101810113_gettyimages-86480026.jpg" width="976" /&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p class="story-body__introduction"&gt;
  There have so far been more than 82,000 global cases of the new coronavirus, more than 78,000 of them in China. The disease, which has spread to more than 50 countries, has been declared a global health emergency, and more than 2,700 people have died.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Here are the BBC News Health team's answers to a range of of readers' questions about the disease.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  I am breastfeeding my five-month-old baby - what should I do if I get coronavirus? - Maeve McGoldrick
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Mothers pass on protection from infection to their babies through their breast milk. If your body is producing antibodies to fight the infection, these would be passed on through breast feeding.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Breastfeeding mums should follow the same advice as anyone else over reducing risk. This is to cover your mouth when you sneeze and cough, throw away a used tissue straight away and wash hands frequently, while trying to avoid touching your eyes, nose or mouth with unwashed hands.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  My mother-in-law, in her 80s, regularly attends church. What's the advice about sharing a communion cup? - Joanna Gordon, Walton-on-Thames
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  A number of churches have issued advice regarding coronavirus.
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.churchofengland.org/more/media-centre/coronavirus-covid-19-guidance-parishes"&gt;
   The Church of England says that there is no government advice
  &lt;/a&gt;
  suggesting that the use of shared communion cups should be suspended.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div class="bbccom_slot mpu-ad" id="bbccom_mpu_1_2_3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="bbccom_advert"&gt;
   
  &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But it says that intinction - where the communion bread is dipped in wine - is not recommended as it can allow infections to spread, and pose a risk to people with certain allergies.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  And it adds that churches should already be following best-hygiene practices, including advising priests and other church officials at communion to ensure their hands are clean.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Until there is an outbreak in the UK - and it's being passed from person to person, which isn't happening at the moment - sharing a communion cup is no more dangerous than it would be during the average winter when flu is circulating.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape has-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    EPA
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="media-caption__text"&gt;
    Tourists have been quarantined in a Tenerife hotel
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  How do you stand insurance-wise if you have to be quarantined during an overseas holiday? - Mrs Dal, Manchester
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The Association of British Insurers (ABI) says this depends on the type of holiday you booked.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  If you are quarantined while on holiday, you should first approach the company through which you booked it for advice on what to do.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It is expected that the government or authority which imposed the quarantine will cover the costs of food and accommodation.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  If the quarantine period extends beyond the time that you would have spent on holiday you should contact your travel insurer. Depending on your policy, you may be able to claim for out-of-pocket costs associated with an extended stay,
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  If your holiday is booked with a firm that is protected by the Air Travel Organisers' Licensing scheme, then you should be covered for the cost of the return flights.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  That usually applies to package holidays only. For flight-only arrangements, the ABI says, this will depend on your travel insurance cover.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In addition, if you have arranged your own travel and accommodation you should check the details of your insurance cover.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  You can read the ABI's
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.abi.org.uk/products-and-issues/topics-and-issues/coronavirus-qa/"&gt;
   detailed advice on coronavirus and travel here.
  &lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  How dangerous is coronavirus for people who, like me, have asthma? - Lesley-Anne, Falkirk
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Respiratory infections, such as coronavirus, can trigger the symptoms of asthma.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Asthma UK advises those who are concerned about the virus to follow a series of steps to manage their asthma.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  These include taking a preventer inhaler daily as prescribed. This helps cut the risk of an asthma attack being triggered by any respiratory virus, including coronavirus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  If asthma symptoms become worse at any point, call NHS 111 or make a next-day GP appointment. Anyone having an asthma attack should follow the steps on their asthma action plan and call 999 for an ambulance if needed.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Asthma UK's full advice regarding coronavirus
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.asthma.org.uk/about/media/news/coronavirus/"&gt;
   can be found here
  &lt;/a&gt;
  .
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  If my husband and I got the virus, could our pets be infected? - Pat Jackson
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  No. According to the World Health Organization there is no evidence that coronavirus can be transmitted between humans and your family pet.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Coronaviruses occur in almost all animal species, including humans. They are usually specific to a single species and transmission between species is very uncommon.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But you should still make sure that after touching your pets you wash your hands regularly with soap and water. Pets can carry bacteria like E.coli and salmonella and these bugs can pass between pets and humans.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  My boss has been in contact with someone who has had to self-quarantine due to coronavirus. Should I also self-quarantine? - Elsie Petherbridge
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51643621"&gt;
   A number of firms
  &lt;/a&gt;
  have asked staff to work from home as a precaution against coronavirus. This was after some of their employees experienced symptoms following a return from affected countries.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But Public Health England (PHE) has said that there is no need to send staff home from work, as most potential cases turn out to be negative. PHE does not recommend closing workplaces, even if there is a confirmed case of coronavirus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  UK health authorities are currently advising people to self-isolate if:
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   They are awaiting a test result for coronavirus
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   They have had close contact with a confirmed infected person
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   They have returned from
   &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/wuhan-novel-coronavirus-information-for-the-public#returning-travellers"&gt;
    some places affected by the virus
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Detailed advice on coronavirus and the workplace
  &lt;a class="story-body__link-external" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/guidance-to-employers-and-businesses-about-covid-19/guidance-for-employers-and-businesses-on-covid-19"&gt;
   can be found here
  &lt;/a&gt;
  .
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  Will people who have already had pneumonia experience milder symptoms from coronavirus? - Marje, Montreal, Canada
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The new coronavirus can, in a small number of cases, lead to pneumonia, most notably in people with pre-existing lung conditions.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  But as this is a new strain of coronavirus, no-one will have any immunity to it. So having had pneumonia, or any other form of coronavirus like Sars, will not provide immunity from this new coronavirus and the lung illness (Covid-19) it can lead to.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The World Health Organization has said it may be 18 months before a vaccine against the coronavirus is publicly available.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  I am five months pregnant and want to understand the risk to the baby if I get infected with coronavirus. BBC website reader
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Scientists don't have any reason to believe that pregnant women are more susceptible to coronavirus than anyone else. PHE says the risk of anyone getting it in the UK is low.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It's important to follow simple hygiene advice to protect yourself from the virus. This includes washing your hands with soap and water often, not touching your face, eyes or mouth with your unwashed hands and avoiding people who are unwell.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  If you believe that you may have coronavirus, have been in contact with someone with the virus, or have travelled from certain parts of the world, the advice is to stay indoors and call the NHS 111 phone service.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  Why are governments going to such extreme measures to combat coronavirus when flu appears to be more deadly? - Lorraine Smith, Harlow
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  These are containment measures to try to stop the virus from becoming a pandemic and spreading freely between people around the world.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Quarantining cities and telling people to stay at home may seem extreme - but the alternative is to let the virus spread unrestrained.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  There is no vaccine for this new virus, as there is for flu, which makes elderly people and those with underlying health conditions very vulnerable to its effects.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  In China, these measures appear to be working as new daily cases of the virus have now started to decline.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul class="story-body__unordered-list"&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-51235105"&gt;
    A visual guide to the outbreak
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-51048366"&gt;
    What you need to know about the virus
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="story-body__list-item"&gt;
   &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/explainers-51632801"&gt;
    How would the UK tackle a coronavirus outbreak?
   &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-with-caption"&gt;
  &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder"&gt;
   &lt;img class="media-placeholder player-with-placeholder__image narrative-video-placeholder" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/720x405/p084zsx4.jpg" /&gt;
   &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder__caption"&gt;
    Media playback is unsupported on your device
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class="player-with-placeholder"&gt;
    &lt;div class="media-player-wrapper"&gt;
     &lt;figure class="js-media-player-unprocessed media-player"&gt;
     &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class="media-with-caption__caption"&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Media caption
   &lt;/span&gt;
   Watch how germs spread and how you can prevent it
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  Can coronavirus be transmitted by things like door handles and how long does it survive? - Jean Jimenez, Panama
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  If someone infected with the virus coughs on to their hand and then touches something, that surface may become contaminated. Door handles are a good example of a surface that might pose a risk.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  It's not yet known how long the new coronavirus might be able to live on such surfaces. Experts suspect it is hours rather than days but it is best to wash your hands regularly to help reduce the risk of infection and spread of the virus.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  Once you've had coronavirus, will you then be immune? - Denise Mitchell, Bicester, Oxfordshire
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  When people recover from an infection, their body is left with some memory of how to fight it should they encounter it again. This immunity is not always long-lasting or totally efficient, however, and can decrease over time. It is not known how long immunity might last after being infected.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;span class="off-screen"&gt;
    Image copyright
   &lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="story-image-copyright"&gt;
    Getty Images
   &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;h2 class="story-body__crosshead"&gt;
  Is a face mask useful against the virus and how often does it have to be replaced? - Tom Lim, Bali, Indonesia
 &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  There is very little evidence wearing face masks makes a difference. Experts say good hygiene - such as regularly washing your hands and certainly before putting them near your mouth - is vastly more effective.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;hr class="story-body__line" /&gt;
 &lt;figure class="media-landscape no-caption full-width"&gt;
  &lt;span class="image-and-copyright-container"&gt;
   &lt;div class="js-delayed-image-load"&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   What questions do you have about the coronavirus?
  &lt;/strong&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   &lt;i&gt;
    In some cases, your question will be published, displaying your name, age and location as you provide it, unless you state otherwise. Your contact details will never be published. Please ensure you have read our
   &lt;/i&gt;
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/usingthebbc/terms/"&gt;
   terms &amp;amp; conditions
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;
   &lt;i&gt;
    and
   &lt;/i&gt;
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;a class="story-body__link" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/usingthebbc/privacy-policy/"&gt;
   privacy policy
  &lt;/a&gt;
  .
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  Use this form to ask your question:
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 &lt;div style="display: none;"&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 13:24:13 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>